id,open_date,name,location,lat,lon,threat,commodity,max_ptl_release_gallons,description,year,month,commodity_key_tokens,description_key_tokens
10049,2020-02-27,Partially Submerged Recreational Vessel Huron Harbor Marina,"Huron, OH",41.391532,-82.554591,Oil,,,"On February 27, 2020, SSC received notification about a partially submerged white 34' recreational vessel at the Huron Harbor North Marina in Huron, Ohio. There is a light rainbow sheen around the vessel which has been contained with boom placed by the marina. No products requested.",2020,2,,"[('February 27, 2020', 'DATE'), ('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Huron Harbor North Marina', 'FAC'), ('Huron', 'GPE'), ('Ohio', 'GPE'), ('marina', 'LOC')]"
10050,2020-02-27,Whitney Tank Battery 160 Loomis Pass Spill,"Venice, LA, USA",29.116625,-89.18091667,Oil,,,"On February 27, 2020, the USCG Sector New Orleans received a report of a discharge of crude oil from a flow line at the Whitney Garden Island Bay Field; Tank Battery 160 Facility, located near Loomis Pass, in the Pass A Loutre State Wildlife Management.  Discharge is secure. Initial estimates are between 5 and 30bbl. USCG requested fate/trajectory and resources at risk.",2020,2,,"[('February 27, 2020', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans', 'ORG'), ('the Whitney Garden Island Bay Field', 'FAC'), ('160', 'CARDINAL'), ('Loomis Pass', 'FAC'), ('the Pass A Loutre State Wildlife Management', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Discharge', 'PRODUCT'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
10048,2020-02-24,Gray whale carcass,"Port Hueneme, CA",34.14974372,-119.20822620000001,Other,,,"On 24-FEB-2020, NMFS Stranding Coordinator in CA contacted the NOAA SSC regarding a 15??gray whale carcass at Port Hueneme, CA.  No field necropsy is anticipated, so the carcass may be towed offshore late in the day.  NMFS requested a carcass drift estimate to aid in determining how far offshore to tow the carcass so it does not re-beach in the upcoming days.",2020,2,,"[('24-FEB-2020', 'CARDINAL'), ('NMFS Stranding Coordinator', 'PERSON'), ('CA', 'ORG'), ('NOAA', 'ORG'), ('Port Hueneme', 'FAC'), ('CA', 'GPE'), ('late in the day', 'TIME'), ('NMFS', 'ORG'), ('the upcoming days', 'DATE')]"
10047,2020-02-20,Recreational vessel sunk in Anacortes Skyline Marina,"2400 Skyline Way, Anacortes, WA 98221, USA",48.49255855,-122.6803676,Oil,,,"On February 20, 2020, the SEA WOLF, a 44 foot recreational vessel sank while moored at the Skyline Marina (2400 Skyline Way, Anacortes, WA 98221). Potential of up to 300 gallons of diesel aboard.",2020,2,,"[('February 20, 2020', 'DATE'), ('44 foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Skyline Marina', 'FAC'), ('2400', 'CARDINAL'), ('Skyline Way', 'GPE'), ('Anacortes', 'ORG'), ('WA', 'ORG'), ('up to 300 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
10046,2020-02-17,North Santiam River - Truck Spill,"N Santiam Hwy, Detroit, OR 97342, USA",44.696999999999996,-122.22689,Oil,,,"On the morning of 16 FEB 2020 along the  Santiam River, a single vehicle crash involving an overturned double fuel tanker occurred releasing approximately 10,000 gallons of gasoline and diesel onto the bank of the Santiam River near mile marker 63. By the end of the day fuel was seen in the river. The EPA FOSC has requested an ESA emergency consultation. The National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS) has been contacted. Consultation is ongoing.",2020,2,,"[('the morning', 'TIME'), ('Santiam River', 'LOC'), ('approximately 10,000 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('the bank of the Santiam River', 'ORG'), ('63', 'CARDINAL'), ('the end of the day', 'DATE'), ('EPA', 'ORG'), ('The National Marine Fisheries Service', 'ORG'), ('NMFS', 'ORG')]"
10045,2020-11-02,Mystery Red Dyed Diesel Spill Venice Marina,"Venice, LA, USA",29.2401303,-89.3645153,Oil,,,"On February 11, 2020, the USCG was notified of a red dyed diesel mystery spill at the Venice Marina, Venice LA. An area of water less than 50x50ft between boat slips contains red dyed diesel and white foam. Quantity unknown. USCG is onsite collecting information and attempting to identify the responsible party. Three dead pelicans found on-site.  NOAA SSC providing phone support. On-scene support is possible.",2020,11,,"[('February 11, 2020', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Marina', 'LOC'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Three', 'CARDINAL')]"
10044,2020-07-02,Diesel Spill - Unknown Source,"Port Orchard, WA. USA",47.54195085,-122.6411712,Oil,,,"On February 07, 2020 - Washington State Department of Ecology, USCG Sector Puget Sound, Washington State Department of Fish and Wildlife, and the City of Port Orchard are on-scene investigating the source of a diesel spill in Yachtfish Marina, Sinclair Inlet, Port Orchard. No impacts to fish or wildlife have been reported and NOAA support is not requested at this time. This is a notification only.",2020,7,,"[('February 07', 'DATE'), ('2020', 'CARDINAL'), ('Washington State Department of Fish and', 'ORG'), ('the City of Port Orchard', 'GPE'), ('Yachtfish Marina', 'LOC'), ('Sinclair Inlet', 'GPE'), ('Port Orchard', 'FAC')]"
10041,2020-07-02,"Fishing Vessel Aground on Shackleford Banks, NC","Harkers Island, NC, USA",34.65218888,-76.62304698,Oil,Diesel Fuel,10000.0,,2020,7,[],
10043,2020-07-02,Lost dredge Hose,Atlantic Ocean,29.61666667,-80.71666667,Other,,,"On February 7, 2020, the NOAA SSC was notified of a lost 2000??length x 36??diameter floating rubber hose that is used to attach to a dredge and pump sand through.  The hose came unattached from the towing vessel M/V TRIDENT sometime on the morning of February 6, 2020,  roughly 28 miles NNE of Daytona Beach, FL. ERD was requested to run a drift study on the estimated position and direction of drift of the rubber hose",2020,7,,"[('February 7, 2020', 'DATE'), ('2000??length', 'CARDINAL'), ('36??diameter', 'CARDINAL'), ('the morning of February 6, 2020', 'TIME'), ('roughly 28 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Daytona Beach', 'GPE'), ('FL', 'GPE')]"
10040,2020-06-02,Gaubert Oil Diesel Spill,"ICW, Houma, LA, USA",29.598269000000002,-90.663037,Oil,,,"On February 6, 2020, a broken valve at a fueling facility located along the Houma ICW at mm52 resulted in the discharge of several hundred gallons of red dye diesel into the ICW.  Local winds pushed the diesel against the bank and into a boat slip. Boom applied and cleanup in progress.",2020,6,,"[('February 6, 2020', 'DATE'), ('ICW', 'ORG'), ('mm52', 'PRODUCT'), ('several hundred gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('ICW', 'ORG')]"
10042,2020-06-02,Small plane crash,"Arcata Bay, Eureka, CA",40.824202,-124.14216040000001,Oil,Aviation fuel,195.0,,2020,6,[],
10036,2020-03-02,GARROW BEND Sunken Tug,"Mobile River, AL",30.655199,-88.0429989,Oil,,,"On February 3, 2020, the USCG Sector Mobile notified the NOAA SSC of tug sunk near the Barry Steam Plant in the Mobile River. An estimated 50-80 gallons of diesel and small amounts of oil/lube was discharged.  The release is contained and OSRO onscene.Notification only. No further action anticipated. Salvage efforts underway.",2020,3,,"[('February 3, 2020', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('the Barry Steam Plant', 'FAC'), ('the Mobile River', 'LOC'), ('An estimated 50-80 gallons', 'CARDINAL'), ('OSRO', 'ORG')]"
10037,2020-03-02,"Grounded Vessel, Hilo, Hawaii","Hilo, HI",19.74280556,-155.08875,Oil,,,"On the evening of February 3, 2020, a 70??motorsailer ran aground on rocks north west of Hilo Harbor on the Big Island of Hawaii.  USCG Sector Honolulu requested a trajectory in the event the vessel discharges its contents of 1200 - 1800 gallons of diesel.  USCG is planning to take action at first light tomorrow morning.",2020,3,,"[('the evening of February 3, 2020', 'TIME'), ('70??motorsailer', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hilo Harbor', 'PERSON'), ('the Big Island', 'FAC'), ('Hawaii', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Sector Honolulu', 'PERSON'), ('1200 - 1800 gallons', 'TIME'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('first light tomorrow morning', 'TIME')]"
10038,2020-03-02,Mystery Oil Slick Viosca Knoll Block 989,Gulf of Mexico,28.935,-88.635,Oil,,,03 Feb 2020 USCG Sec NOLA requested assistance from NOAA NESDIS regarding an offshore mystery oil slick in the Gulf of Mexico Viosca Knoll Block 989 (NRC 1270287). 04 Feb 2020 two additional mystery oil slicks were reported in the vicinity (NRC 1270338 & 1270346). USCG requested a trajectory to determine potential shoreline impact and an assessment of the potential relationship between the three slicks.,2020,3,,"[('03 Feb 2020', 'CARDINAL'), ('NOAA NESDIS', 'ORG'), ('the Gulf of Mexico', 'LOC'), ('989', 'CARDINAL'), ('NRC', 'ORG'), ('1270287', 'DATE'), ('04', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('NRC 1270338 & 1270346', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('three', 'CARDINAL')]"
10035,2020-01-02,"Tabbs Bay Discharge, Baytown, TX","Baytown, TX 77520, USA",29.709034499999998,-94.9843738,Oil,,,"On February 1, 2020, the USCG Sector Houston was notified of 10 - 15 bbl of dark crude oil discharging into Tabbs Bay, located northeast of Texas Ship Channel. The source was reported to be a well head pipeline but the reason for the discharge is currently unknown.  USCG called NOAA requesting trajectory. The source is reportedly secured.",2020,1,,"[('February 1, 2020', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('10 - 15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tabbs Bay', 'LOC'), ('Texas Ship Channel', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('NOAA', 'ORG')]"
10039,2020-01-30,Mystery Sheen Mississippi River mm93,"New Orleans, LA, USA",29.95,-90.01972222,Oil,,,"In January 30, 2020, the USCG Sector NOLA received NRC report 1270027 regarding a 1 mile rainbow sheen at Mississippi River mm93 (just down river of downtown New Orleans).  USCG identified dark product pooled along the LDB at mm94.  No source idendified. USCG contracted OSRO to conduct clean up.   No observed impacts to wildlife. No requests for NOAA assistance at this time.",2020,1,,"[('January 30, 2020', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('NRC', 'ORG'), ('1270027', 'DATE'), ('1 mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mississippi River mm93', 'FAC'), ('New Orleans', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('LDB', 'ORG'), ('mm94', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('OSRO', 'ORG')]"
10034,2020-01-27,Buoy Adrift and Lost: Long Island Sound,"Southold, NY, USA",41.22944444,-72.06638889,Other,,,"On January 27, 2020, the US Coast Guard Sector Long Island Sound contacted the NOAA SSC for assistance in locating a navigational buoy that parted its anchor chain and drifted away sometime before 24 January 2020.  Both NOAA ORR/ERD and the NOAA Navigation Manager are involved.",2020,1,,"[('January 27, 2020', 'DATE'), ('the US Coast Guard', 'ORG'), ('24 January 2020', 'DATE'), ('ORR/ERD', 'ORG'), ('the NOAA Navigation', 'PRODUCT')]"
10033,2020-01-26,Diesel and sulfuric acid discharge in Mississippi River MM 123,"Destrehan, LA",29.95365,-90.393498,Chemical,Sulfuric Acid,,"On January 26, 2020, the NOAA Regional Response Officer (RRO) received notification from the USCG IMD Sector New Orleans about a vessel sinking at MM 123 and actively discharging diesel into Mississippi River. One of its barge is also actively discharging sulfuric acid into the river.  The NOAA RRO is working with the ERD Chemistry and Oceanography Team",2020,1,[],"[('January 26, 2020', 'DATE'), ('the NOAA Regional Response Officer', 'PRODUCT'), ('the USCG IMD Sector New Orleans', 'ORG'), ('MM', 'ORG'), ('Mississippi River', 'LOC'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('The NOAA RRO', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the ERD Chemistry', 'ORG')]"
10032,2020-01-24,50 gal diesel spill Old Fort Bayou NRC 1269451,"Ocean Springs, MS",30.419132,-88.827474,Oil,,,"At 1300 on 24 JAN 2020, USCG Sector Mobile notified SSC of an approximate 50 gallon spill of diesel into the Old Fort Bayou marsh off Highway 609 in Ocean Springs, MS. Discharge was suspected to be from a commercial vessel located near by. USCG collected samples for fingerprinting and hired an OSRO to conduct cleanup. No further support requested.",2020,1,,"[('1300', 'DATE'), ('24 JAN 2020', 'DATE'), ('USCG Sector Mobile', 'ORG'), ('an approximate 50 gallon', 'QUANTITY'), ('Highway 609', 'FAC'), ('Ocean Springs', 'GPE'), ('Discharge', 'PERSON'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('OSRO', 'ORG')]"
10031,2020-01-19,Possible sheen report,"Sea Ranch, CA",38.7,-123.43299999999999,Oil,Petroleum,,"On January 19, 2020, the USCG Sector San Francisco contacted their NOAA SSC regarding a pilot report of a possible sheen off northern CA coast, roughly 29 miles upcoast from Bodega Bay, CA.  USCG requested trajectory support.",2020,1,[],"[('January 19, 2020', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector San Francisco', 'ORG'), ('roughly 29 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Bodega Bay', 'ORG'), ('CA', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
10030,2020-01-16,LifeMed Airplane Crash,"Unalaska, AK",53.909440000000004,-166.55638000000002,Oil,Jet A fuel,170.0,,2020,1,[],
10029,2020-01-14,FV Pappy's Pride,"Galveston, TX, USA",29.33719257,-94.68285995,Oil,,,"On January 14, 2020, the 81-foot fishing vessel Pappy's Pride capsized after a collision with the 600-foot chemical tanker Bow Fortune near the Galveston jetties in Galveston, Texas.  Two fishermen were rescued. The search for the remaining two fishermen is ongoing.  Potential 14,000 gallons red-dyed diesel, tanks compromised at time of impact. USCG requested trajectory and resources at risk. The cause of the collision is under investigation.",2020,1,,"[('January 14, 2020', 'DATE'), ('Bow Fortune', 'PERSON'), ('Galveston', 'GPE'), ('Galveston', 'GPE'), ('Texas', 'GPE'), ('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('14,000 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('trajectory', 'CARDINAL')]"
10028,2020-01-01,FV Scandies Rose sinking,"Sutwik Island, Alaska",56.491719999999994,-157.0178,Oil,diesel,120000.0,,2020,1,[],
10027,2019-12-20,Port of Coos Bay Ammonia Release,"63534 Kingfisher Rd, Coos Bay, OR",43.34598594,-124.324699,Chemical,,,"On December 20, 2019, the USCG Station Coos Bay, Oregon, called the NOAA Emergency Response Division to request an air plume model for a potential ammonia release.  A seafood processing facility at the Port is on fire and there is concern about a 300 lb ammonia cylinder. Status of the tank is unknown. Area being evacuated.  Hazmat team en route.",2019,12,,"[('December 20, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Station Coos Bay', 'PRODUCT'), ('Oregon', 'GPE'), ('the NOAA Emergency Response Division', 'ORG'), ('Port', 'LOC'), ('300', 'CARDINAL')]"
10026,2019-12-18,F/V MANDY JANE sunk,"off San Francisco, CA",37.74,-122.72,Oil,diesel,1000.0,,2019,12,[],
10025,2019-12-17,Sea View Harbor Vessel Fire,"Mystic Islands, NJ 08087, USA",39.55361244,-74.42468265,Oil,Diesel Fuel,2000.0,,2019,12,[],
10022,2019-12-15,M/V Levant - Pier Allision,"Ferndale, WA",48.8515219,-122.59132859999998,Oil,,,"On December 15, 2019, NOAA ERD was notified of an allision between a 741-foot LPG carrier and a pier in Ferndale, WA. The allision occurred at 0445 PST and the damaged vessel was carrying a reported 33,000 tons of propane/butane. The water surrounding the vessel is reported to be free of sheen and NOAA support is not requested at this time (notification only).",2019,12,,"[('December 15, 2019', 'DATE'), ('NOAA ERD', 'ORG'), ('LPG', 'ORG'), ('Ferndale', 'GPE'), ('WA', 'ORG'), ('0445', 'DATE'), ('PST', 'ORG'), ('33,000 tons', 'QUANTITY')]"
10023,2019-12-15,M/V TECUMSEH Engine Room Fire,"Windsor, ON, Canada",42.2772,-83.1011,Oil,Diesel,42000.0,,2019,12,[],
10024,2019-12-14,"Whitney Oil & Gas Tank Battery 49, Garden Island Bay","Venice, LA 70091, USA",29.07554167,-89.16472222,Oil,,,"On December 14, 2019, at approximately 0733 hrs, Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) received NRC#1266407 reporting of approximately 23-25 bbls of crude oil discharged from a broken reducer on the discharge side of a pump, which serviced a 2??flowline between the Dry Oil Tank and storage barge at the Tank Battery 49 facility, located in Garden Island Bay in Plaquemines Parish. SSC Notified",2019,12,,"[('December 14, 2019', 'DATE'), ('Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('NRC#1266407', 'CARDINAL'), ('approximately 23-25', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Dry Oil Tank', 'ORG'), ('49', 'CARDINAL'), ('Garden Island Bay', 'LOC')]"
10021,2019-10-12,Barge Ironmaster Tug Anglian Lady Aground,"ON, Canada",42.51585,-82.68455,Oil,,,"On the morning of December 8, 2019, Barge Ironmaster and Tug Anglian Lady ran aground near the border in Lake St. Clair.  3,500L of diesel on board. No spill observed.   CANUSLAK Notification/Activation at 1800 10 Dec.",2019,10,,"[('the morning of December 8, 2019', 'TIME'), ('Barge Ironmaster', 'PERSON'), ('Tug Anglian', 'PERSON'), ('Lake St. Clair', 'GPE'), ('3,500L', 'CARDINAL'), ('1800 10 Dec.', 'DATE')]"
10020,2019-09-12,Finley BNSF Diesel Spill Hover Park,"Kennewick, WA",46.1235,-118.9908,Oil,,,"December 09, 2019 - Washington State Department of Ecology notified NOAA ERD of an approximately 500 gallon diesel release from a rail car over 11 miles of track near the Columbia River. EPA is the federal response agency.",2019,9,,"[('December 09, 2019', 'DATE'), ('Washington State Department of Ecology', 'ORG'), ('NOAA ERD', 'ORG'), ('an approximately 500 gallon', 'QUANTITY'), ('11 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Columbia River', 'LOC'), ('EPA', 'ORG')]"
10019,2019-09-12,F/V SEA ANGELS Grounding,Browns Inlet NC,34.59349937,-77.23123169,Oil,Diesel Fuel,18000.0,,2019,9,[],
10017,2019-04-12,Lake Pelto Equipment Failure,"Chauvin, LA 70344, USA",29.05986944,-90.72756111,Oil,Crude Oil,630.0,,2019,4,[],
10018,2019-02-12,Bayou Bouillion Vessel Discharge,"Parish Governing Authority District 5, LA, USA",30.26916667,-91.61416667,Oil,Oil,,"On December 2, 2019, the USCG received a report of an unknown amount of Louisiana sweet crude discharge from a hole on a permanently moored barge in the Atchafalaya river. SSC notified. NRC# 1265267",2019,2,[],"[('December 2, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Louisiana', 'GPE'), ('Atchafalaya', 'LOC'), ('NRC', 'ORG')]"
10015,2019-02-12,Pleasure Craft MARCHELLE aground,"West side of Catalina Island, CA",33.419000000000004,-118.488,Oil,Diesel,800.0,,2019,2,[],
10016,2019-11-27,"Grounded vessel, Kauai, HI","Fuji Beach, Kauai, HI",22.06333333,-159.31799999999998,Oil,gasoline,70.0,"On the morning of November 26, USCG Sector Honolulu was notified of a 20-foot rigid hull inflatable boat beached and soft aground on Fuji Beach, Kauai, HI, on the shoreline adjacent to the World Mark Hotel Kapa?�a Shore.  The vessel was overturned and discharging gasoline at a steady drip through the tank fuel cap.  The tank appeared to be intact and the discharge was initially being captured.  By the morning of November 27, the vessel had re-righted itself in the overnight tide and surf and was grounded further up on the beach.  There was no longer any sign of discharge.  USCG requested an assessment of trajectory and persistence of potential discharge of the gasoline on board, assuming a worst-case of 70 gallons based on tank capacity.  Verbal support was provided.  By the early afternoon of November 27, the vessel had been pulled out of the water and the owner had craned it onto a trailer.  No release of gasoline was reported.",2019,11,[],"[('the morning of November 26', 'TIME'), ('Sector Honolulu', 'PERSON'), ('Fuji Beach', 'GPE'), ('Kauai', 'GPE'), ('the World Mark', 'ORG'), ('the morning of November 27', 'TIME'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('70 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('the early afternoon of November 27', 'TIME')]"
10014,2019-11-27,TPC Port Neches Explosion,"Nederland, Texas",29.97694444,-93.94722222,Chemical,butadiene,,"On November 27, 2019, a tank at the TPC facility in Port Neches, TX exploded.  Current reports indicate the tank contained butadiene.  Facility caught fire.  MSU Port Arthur contacted NOAA SSC to request air plume model.  NOAA SSC has coordinated with NWS Lake Charles, and provided Hysplit model to MSU Port Arthur, along with chemical information for butadiene.",2019,11,[],"[('November 27, 2019', 'DATE'), ('TPC', 'PRODUCT'), ('Port Neches', 'GPE'), ('TX', 'ORG'), ('Facility', 'ORG'), ('MSU', 'ORG'), ('NWS Lake Charles', 'ORG'), ('MSU Port Arthur', 'ORG')]"
10013,2019-11-22,Kitoi Bay Hatchery Release,"Afognak Island, AK",58.190830000000005,-152.37027,Oil,diesel,1200.0,,2019,11,[],
10011,2019-11-17,"Tugboat Miss Bonnie Allision, Oregon Inlet, NC","Herbert C. Bonner Bridge, Oregon Inlet, NC",35.77281188,-75.53485106,Oil,Diesel Fuel,500.0,,2019,11,[],
10012,2019-11-16,Crowley Barge 650-2 Crude Oil Spill,"Anacortes, WA",48.50453554,-122.57486340000001,Oil,,,"Saturday, November 16, 2019 3:14 AM - An estimated 20 gallons of Alaska North Slope Crude was spilled onto the deck of a barge during transfer operations in North Puget Sound, Washington. It was estimated that 5 gallons entered the water. On Sunday morning, Washington State's Department of Ecology gave final approval of the cleanup. Investigation into root cause is ongoing.",2019,11,,"[('Saturday, November 16, 2019', 'DATE'), ('An estimated 20 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('Alaska North Slope Crude', 'ORG'), ('North Puget Sound', 'GPE'), ('Washington', 'GPE'), ('5 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('morning', 'TIME'), (""Washington State's"", 'GPE'), ('Department of Ecology', 'ORG')]"
10009,2019-11-14,OSV BOTRUC 22 spill,"off Sabine Pass, TX",29.675,-93.835,Oil,Diesel,700.0,,2019,11,[],
10008,2019-11-13,Recreational vessel TUSSLER sunk,"off La Jolla, CA",32.8667,-117.6208,Oil,Diesel,800.0,,2019,11,[],
10007,2019-12-11,Onyx Grounding,"Strait Island, AK",56.39666999999999,-133.71667,Oil,diesel,100.0,,2019,12,[],
10010,2019-11-11,TPIC Bayou Perot ISB 2019,"Delta Farms, Barataria, LA",29.642638,-90.18337,Oil,,,"On November 9, 2019, the Texas Petroleum Investment Company (TPIC) discovered a flowline Delta Farm #96 Well developed a leak and released oil into a floating marsh. Less than 1 acre of marsh has been impacted. The current estimate of discharged oil is less than 10bbs.",2019,11,,"[('November 9, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the Texas Petroleum Investment Company', 'ORG'), ('Delta Farm', 'ORG'), ('96', 'MONEY'), ('Less than 1 acre', 'QUANTITY'), ('10bbs', 'DATE')]"
10006,2019-10-11,F/V Miss Haley sunk,off Northern CA,38.45,-123.6,Oil,Diesel,3500.0,,2019,10,[],
10005,2019-07-11,Calcasieu Ship Channel Discharge,"Lake Charles, LA",30.13166667,-93.32055556,Oil,Sweet Louisiana Crude,1400.0,,2019,7,"[('Sweet Louisiana Crude', 'PERSON')]",
10004,2019-06-11,"HFO Spill, Honolulu Harbor, HI","Honolulu Harbor near Piers 19 and 20, Honolulu, HI 96817, USA",21.30847553,-157.8679696,Oil,Heavy Fuel Oil,84.0,,2019,6,[],
10003,2019-01-11,F/V FT Pierce Lady,Atlantic Ocean,25.30027778,-79.6525,Oil,,,"On November 1, 2019, the USCG Sector Miami notified the SSC that the 65 foot wooden fishing vessel Ft Pierce Lady sank 35 miles east of Elliott Key with 1200 gallons of diesel, 22 gallons of gasoline, and 40 gallons of paint onboard. USCG requested a spill trajectory for the incident.",2019,1,,"[('November 1, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Sector Miami', 'PERSON'), ('65 foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('35 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Elliott Key', 'LOC'), ('1200 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('22 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('40 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9998,2019-10-27,Calpine Corp: Propylene Glycol,"9 Bridge St, Weymouth, MA, USA",42.2425,-70.9656,Chemical,,,"On October 27, 2019,  the Calpine Corp. in Weymouth, Ma reported to the USCG that it accidentally released 500-1000 gallons of propylene glycol into into storm drains on the property that eventually lead to the Fore River and into the Boston outer harbor.  Sector Boston contacted the NOAA SSC for information on the fate and toxicity of the product.",2019,10,,"[('October 27, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the Calpine Corp.', 'ORG'), ('Weymouth', 'GPE'), ('Ma', 'PERSON'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('500-1000 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Fore River', 'LOC'), ('Boston', 'GPE'), ('Sector Boston', 'ORG')]"
10001,2019-10-27,"James River, Virginia Diesel Oil Spill","Hampton, VA, USA",36.98032249,-76.34362794,Oil,Diesel Fuel,,"On Sunday, 27 October, 2019, both USCG Sector HamptonRoads and Virginia DEQ notified the NOAA SSC about an oil spill in the vicinity of Outlook Beach, located near the mouth of the James River. Both source and volume spilled are unknown. The product appears to be diesel fuel.",2019,10,[],"[('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('27 October, 2019', 'DATE'), ('Sector HamptonRoads', 'PERSON'), ('Virginia DEQ', 'PERSON'), ('Outlook Beach', 'GPE'), ('the James River', 'LOC')]"
10000,2019-10-27,TPIC Breton Sound 37 Facility Spill,"LA, USA",29.51733333,-89.12563889,Oil,,,"On October 27, 2019, the USCG notified the NOAA SSC of an 8 mile mystery sheen in Breton Sound in the vicinity of the Chandeleur Islands. Later confirmed that source of sheen was a damaged TPIC wellhead 37. USFW is engaged and providing remote support. NOAA provided initial trajectory and will continue support.",2019,10,,"[('October 27, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('8 mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('Breton Sound', 'GPE'), ('the Chandeleur Islands', 'LOC'), ('sheen', 'ORG'), ('37', 'CARDINAL')]"
9999,2019-10-27,Whitney Oil & Gas TB49 Spill,"Venice, LA, USA",29.07519444,-89.16461111,Oil,,,"On October 27, 2019, the USCG was notified of a discharge of crude oil from Whitney Oil & Gas Tank Battery 49 into the Pass A Loutre Wildlife Management Area.",2019,10,,"[('October 27, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Whitney Oil & Gas Tank', 'ORG'), ('49', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Pass A Loutre Wildlife Management Area', 'LAW')]"
9997,2019-10-24,"Grounded Sailboat, Maui, Hawaii","Lahaina, HI , USA",20.80747158,-156.6221237,Oil,Diesel,150.0,,2019,10,[],
9996,2019-10-22,LPG Tanker EPIC BALTA Fire,"Venice, LA, USA",29.20866667,-89.28016667,Oil,,,"On October 22, 2019, the USCG notified the NOAA SSC of LPG Tanker MV EPIC BALTA on fire at Pilottown, LA near Pass a Loutre State Wildlife Management Area.  USCG requesting fate and trajectory",2019,10,,"[('October 22, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('LPG Tanker', 'ORG'), ('Pilottown', 'GPE'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('Pass a Loutre State Wildlife Management Area', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9994,2019-10-21,FMT 3114 Barge MM 480 Mississippi River,"Transylvania, LA , USA",32.732929999999996,-91.1009,Oil,crude oil,,"On October 20, 2019, the USCG MSD Vicksburg (Sector Lower MS River) contacted the NOAA SSC regarding a barge collision on the MS River near mile marker (MM) 480 (about 3 miles south of Lake Providence, Louisiana). The volume of release reported at 40 barrels. The release is reportedly secured with a patch.",2019,10,[],"[('October 20, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Sector Lower', 'ORG'), ('MS River', 'LOC'), ('the MS River', 'LOC'), ('MM', 'PERSON'), ('480', 'CARDINAL'), ('about 3 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Lake Providence', 'GPE'), ('Louisiana', 'GPE'), ('40 barrels', 'QUANTITY')]"
9995,2019-10-21,FV Furious Sea and FV Coral Sea,"Ferndale, WA",48.78985694,-122.7039642,Oil,,,"Monday, October 21, 2019 at 1500 PDT - NOAA ERD was notified of a 55-foot fishing vessel that sank near Sandy Point Marina, Ferndale, Washington. The fuel tanks are reported to be empty and only a small sheen is observed above the sunken vessel. The Coast Guard has federalized the response. This is a notification only - no products are requested at this time.",2019,10,,"[('Monday, October 21, 2019', 'DATE'), ('1500', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sandy Point Marina', 'ORG'), ('Ferndale', 'GPE'), ('Washington', 'GPE'), ('The Coast Guard', 'ORG')]"
9993,2019-10-20,TPIC Romere Pass Well 21 Spill,"Venice, LA, USA",29.275278000000004,-89.24305600000001,Oil,,,"On October 19, 2019,  crude oil spilled from a flow line into a Buras Bayou within Delta National Wildlife Refuge at Well 21.  The well has been shut-in. TPIC reported a 20 ft by 5 ft sheen. Absorbent and containment boom applied. USCG requested Resources at Risk.",2019,10,,"[('October 19, 2019', 'DATE'), ('Buras Bayou', 'ORG'), ('Delta National Wildlife Refuge', 'ORG'), ('21', 'DATE'), ('TPIC', 'PERSON'), ('20 ft by 5 ft', 'QUANTITY'), ('Resources at Risk', 'ORG')]"
9992,2019-10-16,"Silver sheen, Breton Sound Block 27a",LA USA,29.46638889,-89.40916667,Oil,,,"On October 16, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) was notified of a sheen observed by an overflight on 15OCT19 at 1504 CST, originating from a well head in Breton Sound.",2019,10,,"[('October 16, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('15OCT19', 'CARDINAL'), ('Breton Sound', 'GPE')]"
9991,2019-10-15,Hilcorp Energy Berrwood E-5 Facility Spill,Gulf of Mexico,28.98435,-89.36036700000001,Oil,,,"On October 15, 2019,  Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) received a report of a discharge of crude oil from a flare associated with the Berrwood E-5 facility, owned/operated by Hilcorp Energy, located in Southwest Pass MM 13 (E5 Canal).  The incident occurred due to an unknown cause.",2019,10,,"[('October 15, 2019', 'DATE'), ('Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('Berrwood', 'ORG'), ('Hilcorp Energy', 'ORG'), ('Southwest Pass MM', 'PERSON'), ('E5 Canal', 'PRODUCT')]"
9990,2019-10-14,Sunken Fishing Vessel AMAK,"Garibaldi, OR",45.55589094,-123.9124088,Oil,,,"Monday, October 14, 2019 at 1044 - USCG Sector Columbia River notified NOAA ERD of a 65-foot commercial fishing vessel carrying a maximum of 1000 gallons of diesel has sunk in the port of Garibaldi, Oregon. Cleanup is underway and Resources at Risk have been requested.",2019,10,,"[('Monday, October 14, 2019', 'DATE'), ('1044', 'DATE'), ('Columbia River', 'LOC'), ('NOAA ERD', 'ORG'), ('1000 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('Garibaldi', 'GPE'), ('Oregon', 'GPE'), ('Resources at Risk', 'ORG')]"
9988,2019-11-10,"Grounded Rec Vessel, San Bernard, TX","Brazoria County, TX, USA",28.85083333,-95.44444444,Oil,Diesel,150.0,,2019,11,[],
9989,2019-11-10,"Sunken Rec Vessel, San Bernard, TX",Gulf of Mexico,28.90933333,-95.17855556,Oil,,,"On October 10, 2019, late in the evening, the sailing vessel Quickxotic sank approximately 2 nautical miles offshore of the mouth of the San Bernard River, with 150 gallons of diesel on board.  There has been no evidence of a discharge.  Vessel is in the same general area as a grounded rec vessel also reported this morning.  Phone support provided.",2019,11,,"[('October 10, 2019', 'DATE'), ('late in the evening', 'TIME'), ('approximately 2', 'CARDINAL'), ('the San Bernard River', 'LOC'), ('150 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('Vessel', 'PRODUCT'), ('this morning', 'TIME')]"
9987,2019-10-10,Corpus Christi Inner Harbor Mystery Spill,"Corpus Christi, TX",27.81888889,-97.44638889,Oil,Oil,7476.0,,2019,10,[],
9984,2019-07-10,M/V RT. HON. PAUL J. MARTIN Aground,"Edwardsburgh/Cardinal, Canada",44.7721,-75.39904,Oil,HFO,64000.0,,2019,7,[],
9983,2019-07-10,TPIC Platform Pipeline Release Block 69,"Venice, LA 70091, USA",29.202092999999998,-89.04312900000001,Oil,,,"On 07OCT19 USCG Sector New Orleans IMD received a report at ~0855 of 1 - 3 bbl crude oil released into a marsh area in the Gulf of Mexico. The cause of the release was due to a seal on a pipeline located in a platform. Fate, trajectory, and resources at risk has been requested .",2019,7,,"[('07OCT19 USCG Sector New Orleans IMD', 'ORG'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Gulf of Mexico', 'LOC')]"
9985,2019-05-10,Phillips 66 Refinery Spill,"Belle Chasse , LA 70036, USA",29.71766667,-90.17,Oil,,,"02 Oct 2019 USCG received notification of a crude oil spill at the Phillip 66 Refinery in Belle Chasse, LA. NOAA SSC assisting with coordination and assessment.",2019,5,,"[('02', 'CARDINAL'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('the Phillip 66 Refinery', 'EVENT'), ('Belle Chasse', 'PERSON'), ('LA', 'GPE')]"
9982,2019-04-10,Sunken Vessel - P/C King's Way,"West Bay Marina, Olympia, WA",47.06638028,-122.9151678,Oil,,,"October 4, 2019 at 1035 PDT - NOAA ERD was notified of the sinking of a 90-foot power vessel at its slip in West Bay Marina, Olympia, Washington. The vessel has an estimated 1,200 gallons of diesel onboard and is actively releasing fuel.",2019,4,,"[('October 4, 2019', 'DATE'), ('1035', 'DATE'), ('West Bay Marina', 'LOC'), ('Olympia', 'GPE'), ('Washington', 'GPE'), ('an estimated 1,200 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9980,2019-02-10,Gray Whale Carcass Movement,"Cook Inlet, AK",59.75493,-152.2479,Other,,,NMFS is requesting a trajectory analysis for a gray whale carcass observed in Cook Inlet on June 17 to see if it may or may not be the same gray whale carcass observed on June 27 and then on July 11. The size and state of decomp make this a possibility. Trajectory analysis may confirm.,2019,2,,"[('NMFS', 'ORG'), ('Cook Inlet', 'GPE'), ('June 17', 'DATE'), ('June 27', 'DATE'), ('July 11', 'DATE')]"
9979,2019-01-10,OSK Dock Collapse,"Nikiski, AK",60.741578000000004,-151.309911,Oil,diesel,300.0,,2019,1,[],
9977,2019-01-10,"Sunken Dredge Tender, Calcasieu Channel",Louisiana,29.86011111,-93.34527778,Oil,diesel fuel,100.0,,2019,1,[],
9978,2019-01-10,Sunken Towing Vessel ITV ROY H.,"Morris, IL",41.385,-88.3243,Oil,Diesel,3000.0,,2019,1,[],
9976,2019-09-30,Capsized Vessel near Duluth Harbor,"Duluth, MN",46.71611111,-92.02277778,Oil,Gasoline,30.0,"On September 30, 2019 a vessel capsized and sank near Duluth in rough weather. The vessel was carrying 30 gallons of gasoline and two 12V batteries on-board.",2019,9,[],"[('September 30, 2019', 'DATE'), ('Duluth', 'LOC'), ('30 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('two 12V', 'CARDINAL')]"
9975,2019-09-28,Vessel Lucky Nguyen allision with well head,"LA, USA",29.04166667,-89.40833333,Oil,,,"On September 28, 2019, the USCG was notified that vessel Lucky Nguyen allided with a plugged and abandoned well west of Southwest Pass. USCG planning salvage operations. Small quantity of diesel discharged from fishing vessel. Diesel contained within boom. SSC providing site conditions, including weather forecast.",2019,9,,"[('September 28, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Southwest Pass', 'ORG')]"
9973,2019-09-25,Mystery Release Port Fourchon,"Golden Meadow, LA, USA",29.1149,-90.199,Chemical,,,"25 Sept 2017, USCG MSU Houma received notification of a mystery product in a drainage ditch adjacent to Bayou Lafourche, Port Fourchon, LA.  A black product with a very strong odor impacted less than 1 mile of the drainage ditch. The product is contained by earthen dam. A responsible party has not yet been identified. USCG hired a contractor to conduct the clean up. USCG has requested assistance from NOAA to characterize the mystery product , determine toxicity of the product and recommend cleanup activities. SSC will provide on-scene support.",2019,9,,"[('25', 'CARDINAL'), ('MSU', 'ORG'), ('Bayou Lafourche', 'PERSON'), ('Port Fourchon', 'PERSON'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('less than 1 mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('NOAA', 'ORG')]"
9972,2019-09-23,Sunken F/V Chocolate Bayou,"Chocolate Bayou TX 77577, USA",29.25305556,-95.23494444,Oil,"engine oil, diesel, hydraulic fluid",400.0,,2019,9,[],
9971,2019-09-20,San Jacinto River Fleet Incident,"Channelview, TX",29.79277778,-95.06166667,Oil,"naptha, monoetheylene glycol, lube oil",420000.0,,2019,9,"[('monoetheylene glycol', 'PERSON')]",
9970,2019-09-19,M/V BRANDON G. BUCHANAN,Mississippi River Mile Marker 387,31.856109999999997,-91.2971,Chemical,,,"On September 19, 2019, the USCG Sector Lower MS River notified the NOAA SSC of a sunken barge carrying 3,200 tons of Urea Ammonium Nitrate (UAN) located at mile marker 387 on the MS River.  SSC provide initial fate and behavior analysis.",2019,9,,"[('September 19, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector Lower', 'ORG'), ('MS River', 'LOC'), ('3,200 tons', 'QUANTITY'), ('Urea Ammonium Nitrate', 'ORG'), ('387', 'CARDINAL'), ('the MS River', 'LOC')]"
9969,2019-09-18,Right Whale Hindcast,"Babylon, NY, USA",40.60783889,-73.29096944,Other,,,"On Sept 16, 2019 a dead Atlantic Right Whale (highly endangered) was observed.   The NMFS Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office (GARFO) requested a hindcast of the carcass from the NOAA SSC and NOAA ERD.",2019,9,,"[('Sept 16, 2019', 'DATE'), ('Atlantic Right Whale', 'ORG'), ('The NMFS Greater Atlantic Regional Fisheries Office', 'ORG'), ('GARFO', 'PERSON'), ('NOAA ERD', 'ORG')]"
9968,2019-09-17,"Longliner Miss Emma on fire off Oahu, HI","Oahu, Hawaii",21.21333333,-157.9016667,Oil,Diesel,1700.0,,2019,9,[],
9966,2019-11-09,Mystery Sheen Mississippi River mm96 Downtown NOLA,"LA, USA",29.95388889,-90.06166667,Oil,,,"On September 11, 2019, the USCG received a report of an unknown dark product around the paddle boat NATCHEZ IVO mile marker 96 in the Mississippi River. A Coast Guard overflight confirmed the dark product and  sheen moving downstream along the left descending bank for approximately ¼ mile. USCG was unable to identify a responsible party and accessed the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund to hire an OSRO.  Boom was placed around the impacted area. SSC and RRO will be onsite Sept 11 to assist.",2019,11,,"[('September 11, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('96', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Mississippi River', 'LOC'), ('Coast Guard', 'ORG'), ('approximately ¼ mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund', 'ORG'), ('OSRO', 'ORG'), ('Boom', 'PERSON'), ('Sept 11', 'DATE')]"
9965,2019-10-09,MV Alice C,"Winthrop, MA",42.16891573,-70.44213982,Oil,,,"On 10 Sept. 2019 the 50 foot MV ALICE-C, a ""live aboard"" vessel at the Atlantis Marina in Winthrop, MA sank at it's slip.  The vessel was carrying approximately 300-400 gallons of gasoline and 100 gallons of diesel or home heating oil (used to the heat the living space).  USCG Sector Boston contacted the NOAA SSC due to the proximity of coastal marsh lands.",2019,10,,"[('10 Sept. 2019', 'DATE'), ('50 foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('ALICE-C', 'ORG'), ('the Atlantis Marina', 'LOC'), ('Winthrop', 'GPE'), ('MA', 'GPE'), ('approximately 300', 'CARDINAL'), ('100 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG Sector Boston', 'ORG')]"
9964,2019-08-09,MV Kristin Faye,Gulf of Mexico,29.30166111,-89.05499722,Oil,,,"On September 8, 2019, the USCG received a report that Lift Boat M/V KRISTIN FAYE was partially submerged due to a punch through of the ocean floor with the lift boats port leg in Main Pass Block 64. 700 gallons of diesel and 200 gallons of hydraulic oil onboard with a reported 55 gallons of diesel discharged into the waterway resulting in. 3 mile sheen at time of report.",2019,8,,"[('September 8, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Lift Boat M/V KRISTIN FAYE', 'PERSON'), ('Main Pass Block 64', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('700 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('200 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('55 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('3 mile', 'QUANTITY')]"
9963,2019-08-09,MV Savage Voyager,"99 Lock and Dam Rd, Dennis, MS 38838, USA",34.521359999999994,-88.323718,Oil,diluted bitumen (Cold Lake Blend),281400.0,,2019,8,[],
9962,2019-08-09,St. Simons Sound Incident,"Brunswick, GA 31323, USA",31.13,-81.41333333,Oil,,,"On September 8, 2019, the USCG contacted the NOAA SSC to report a RORO vessel, the Golden Ray had capsized off Brunswick, Georgia. The vessel was on fire. USCG was conducting rescue operations. NOAA will provide an initial trajectory analysis and Resources at Risk report. The NWS is providing spot forecasts for the incident.",2019,8,,"[('September 8, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('NOAA', 'ORG'), ('the Golden Ray', 'FAC'), ('Brunswick', 'GPE'), ('Georgia', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Resources at Risk report', 'WORK_OF_ART')]"
9961,2019-04-09,DOW Chemical Benzene Release Mississippi River,"Hahnville, LA 70057, USA",29.993000000000002,-90.44116667,Chemical,,,"On Sept 4 2019, USCG was notified of a benzene release into the Mississippi River at mm 127 from the DOW Chemical facility in Hahnville, LA.  DOW reported that the release exceeded the reportable quantity (10 lbs). Cause of the release is unknown.",2019,4,,"[('Sept 4 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('the Mississippi River', 'LOC'), ('mm 127', 'FAC'), ('DOW Chemical', 'ORG'), ('Hahnville', 'GPE'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('DOW', 'ORG'), ('10', 'CARDINAL')]"
9960,2019-08-29,Hurricane Dorian,United States,28.14950321,-80.33203125,Other,,,NOAA Office of Response and Restoration Emergency Response Division initiated this Response Link Hotline 29 August 2019 to begin cataloging NOAA OR&R response activities associated with Hurricane Dorian.,2019,8,,"[('NOAA Office of Response and Restoration Emergency Response Division', 'ORG'), ('29 August 2019', 'DATE'), ('OR&R', 'ORG'), ('Hurricane Dorian', 'GPE')]"
9959,2019-08-27,Aground/Sunken Vessel T/V Rawhide,"Northport, MI",45.128659999999996,-85.60978,Oil,Diesel,,"On the morning of August 27, 2019 at 7:48 a.m., the Coast Guard received a report of the towing vessel Rawhide, sunk in Northport Bay. Local first responders reported an oil sheen near the vessel. Salvage operations have begun.",2019,8,[],"[('the morning of August 27, 2019', 'TIME'), ('7:48 a.m.', 'TIME'), ('the Coast Guard', 'ORG'), ('Northport Bay', 'LOC'), ('first', 'ORDINAL')]"
9957,2019-08-25,"Pleasure craft ""The Lady"" sunk","Huntington Beach, CA",33.7283,-118.0745,Oil,Diesel,600.0,,2019,8,[],
9956,2019-08-16,ArcelorMittal Burns Harbor,"Cook County, IL, USA",42.01666667,-87.25,Chemical,Cyanide,,"The USCG Sector Chicago was notified of an on-going release of ""free cyanide"" from the ArcelorMittal facility in Gary, Indiana from their holding lagoon to the Little Calumet River.  Sector contacted NOAA for support information on 16 Aug 2019.",2019,8,[],"[('ArcelorMittal', 'ORG'), ('Gary', 'GPE'), ('Indiana', 'GPE'), ('the Little Calumet River', 'FAC'), ('16 Aug 2019', 'DATE')]"
9955,2019-08-15,Time Energy Cox Bay Crude Spill and In-situ Burn,"LA, USA",29.47583333,-89.63527778,Oil,,,"On August 15, 2019, the USCG was notified of a crude oil spill from a Time Energy flow line in Cox Bay. A reported 20 bbl have impacted approx 200 x 600ft of marsh. Source is secured and the USCG requested evaluation of potential to conduct an in-situ burn.",2019,8,,"[('August 15, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Time Energy', 'ORG'), ('Cox Bay', 'LOC'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('200', 'CARDINAL'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9954,2019-08-13,"Disabled pleasure craft, Lanai, Hawaii","Maui County, HI, USA",20.9425,-156.89233330000002,Oil,Diesel,800.0,,2019,8,[],
9953,2019-12-08,Napakiak School Tank Farm,"Napakiak, AK",60.6943,-161.9696,Oil,,,"On 12-Aug-2019, USCG Sector Anchorage reported that the Napakiak School fuel tank farm is at risk from bank erosion along the Kuskokwim River. The potential for discharge is 36000 gallons of home heating oil. Sector requested NOAA assistance in contacting experts and gathering information regarding river bank erosion risk at this location.",2019,12,,"[('12-Aug-2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG Sector Anchorage', 'ORG'), ('the Napakiak School', 'ORG'), ('the Kuskokwim River', 'LOC'), ('36000 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9950,2019-09-08,Hilcorp Crude spill Terrebonne Bay,"LA, USA",29.21777778,-90.50277778,Oil,,,"On Aug 9, 2019, the USCG notified the NOAA SSC of a sheen in Terrebonne Bay, LA.  A reported 2bbl of Louisiana sweet crude spilled from a Hilcorp facility. Some dark product is contained within boom but a rainbow sheen is escaping containment. USCG requested trajectory.",2019,9,,"[('Aug 9, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Terrebonne Bay', 'LOC'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('2bbl', 'CARDINAL'), ('Louisiana', 'GPE'), ('Hilcorp', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9952,2019-09-08,"S2 Energy Little lake, Turtle Bay, Jefferson Parrish, LA","Parish Governing Authority District 1, LA, USA",29.53111111,-90.13194444,Oil,oil,,"On August 09, 2019 at approximately 1459 CDT, Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) received NRC#1254713 reporting a discharge of an unknown amount of crude oil into Little Lake, Turtle Bay, Jefferson Parish, from inactive wellhead 2453#4, owned/operated by S2 ENERGY.",2019,9,[],"[('August 09, 2019', 'DATE'), ('approximately 1459', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('NRC#1254713', 'CARDINAL'), ('Little Lake', 'LOC'), ('Turtle Bay', 'LOC'), ('Jefferson Parish', 'PERSON'), ('2453#4', 'CARDINAL'), ('ENERGY', 'ORG')]"
9951,2019-08-08,TPIC South Pass 24 W1 Central Facility,"9, LA, USA",29.08722222,-89.28555556,Oil,oil,,"On August 8, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans CDT received a report of a discharge of an estimated 05 barrels of crude oil into South West Pass, Plaquemines Parish, near Joseph Bayou, from a hatch malfunction on a saltwater/oil storage tank at the South Pass 24 W1 Central Facility, owned/operated by Texas Petroleum Investment Company (TPIC). A representative for TPIC stated that upon discovery of the discharge, facility personnel immediately secured source in order to prevent further discharge.",2019,8,[],"[('August 8, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans', 'ORG'), ('an estimated 05 barrels', 'QUANTITY'), ('South West Pass', 'LOC'), ('Joseph Bayou', 'PERSON'), ('the South Pass 24 W1 Central Facility', 'FAC'), ('Texas Petroleum Investment Company', 'ORG')]"
9949,2019-07-08,"Mystery Sheen, Southeast Oahu, Hawaii","China Walls, Oahu",21.25777778,-157.7075,Other,,,"On August 7, 2019, the U.S. Coast Guard Sector Honolulu contacted the NOAA SSC to request support related to a mystery sheen reported off the China Walls and Spitting Cave area near Hawaii Kai on the Island of Oahu, Hawaii. The sheen was reported to USCG as approximately 1 mile long and 20 meters wide, appearing orange/brown in color and looking like emulsified oil.  USCG requested an assessment of whether the sheen, if confirmed to be oil, could potentially impact nearby shorelines.  A verbal trajectory was provided.  After investigation, USCG determined the sheen was of biological origin.",2019,7,,"[('August 7, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the U.S. Coast Guard', 'ORG'), ('Sector Honolulu', 'PERSON'), ('the China Walls', 'ORG'), ('Spitting Cave', 'LOC'), ('Hawaii Kai', 'FAC'), ('the Island of Oahu', 'LOC'), ('Hawaii', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('1 mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('20 meters', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9944,2019-02-08,Grounded F/V Koko,"Cape Disappointment, Ilwaco, Washington",46.28835917,-124.0481758,Oil,Marine Diesel,,"On Friday, August 02, 2019 at 0830 PDT NOAA ERD was notified of a 40 foot fiberglass hull fishing vessel hard aground off Cape Disappointment State Park, Washington. In the early morning hours, the vessel missed a channel marker and grounded on charted pilings from an old structure. As the tide ebbed, the vessel remained stuck and capsized above the pilings. At least one 12-inch crack in the vessel's hull was observed to be leaking fuel. Vessel owner-hired contractors worked with Washington State Department of Ecology to place containment boom around the vessel.  The USCG requested a trajectory.  The vessel was successfully de-fueled on Saturday (8/3) and removed from the water on Sunday (8/4).",2019,2,"[('Marine Diesel', 'PERSON')]","[('Friday, August 02, 2019', 'DATE'), ('0830', 'DATE'), ('PDT NOAA ERD', 'ORG'), ('40 foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('Cape Disappointment State Park', 'GPE'), ('Washington', 'GPE'), ('the early morning hours', 'TIME'), ('Washington State Department of Ecology', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('8/3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('8/4', 'CARDINAL')]"
9943,2019-07-31,Sodium Dimethyldithiocarbamate Release near Sevenmile Creek,"Harborcreek, PA",42.165777,-79.950408,Chemical,Sodium Dimethyldithiocarbamate,,"At 0330 on July 31, 2019 a tank with 200 lbs of Hydrofluoric Acid was reported to be leaking onto the ground near Sevenmile Creek. ALOHA plume modeling was requested.",2019,7,[],"[('0330', 'DATE'), ('July 31, 2019', 'DATE'), ('200', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hydrofluoric Acid', 'GPE'), ('Sevenmile Creek', 'GPE'), ('ALOHA', 'ORG')]"
9945,2019-07-30,Sunken Vessel Crane Barge at ARTCO,"Waggaman, LA",29.94466667,-90.22472222,Oil,Oil,,"On August 30, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans IMD was notified of a sunken crane barge at ARTCOs (AMERICAN RIVER TRANSPORTATION CO) Mile Marker 110 fleeting area. A light, sporadic sheen  was seen coming from the vicinity of the sunken barge.",2019,7,[],"[('August 30, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans IMD', 'ORG'), ('AMERICAN RIVER TRANSPORTATION CO', 'ORG'), ('110', 'CARDINAL')]"
9942,2019-07-29,Sunken Tugboat Meagan M.,"Port Orchard Railway Marina, WA",47.54,-122.64,Oil,,,"On July 29, 2019, the USCG Sector Puget Sound notified NOAA ERD of a sunken tug boat at its slip in Railway Marina, Port Orchard, WA. An estimated 200 gallons of marine diesel has released with moderate sheen. Maximum potential for product onboard is unknown. OSROs are in route.",2019,7,,"[('July 29, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector Puget Sound', 'LAW'), ('NOAA ERD', 'ORG'), ('Railway Marina', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Port Orchard', 'GPE'), ('WA', 'ORG'), ('An estimated 200 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9941,2019-07-28,Barataria Bay  Potential Platform Spill,Barataria Bay,29.33166667,-89.95,Oil,Oil,,On 28JUL19 at ~ 2049 CDT NOAA RRO received a phone call from USCG Sector New Orleans IMD  asking for 2 fates and trajectories for a 35 bbl and 1 - 3 bbl oil spill in Barataria Bay from a platform discharge. Sheen was seen but no dark oil at the time the NRC report was generated.,2019,7,[],"[('28JUL19', 'DATE'), ('USCG Sector New Orleans IMD', 'ORG'), ('2', 'CARDINAL'), ('35', 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Barataria Bay', 'LOC'), ('Sheen', 'ORG'), ('NRC', 'ORG')]"
9940,2019-07-25,MV Catalyst Grounding,"Admiralty Island, Alaska",57.83616,-134.29653000000002,Oil,diesel,3000.0,,2019,7,[],
9946,2019-07-25,"TPIC Discharge Romere Pass, Delta National Wildlife Refuge","Romere Pass Seaplane Base, Venice, LA 70091, USA",29.27444444,-89.24194444,Oil,Oil,30.0,"On July 25, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans IMD received a report of a discharge of an estimated 30 gallons of crude oil into a marsh area, in Romere Pass, of the Delta National Wildlife Refuge, from a 4-inch flow line, associated with the Delta Duck Facility, owned/operated by Texas Petroleum Investment Company (TPIC).",2019,7,[],"[('July 25, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans IMD', 'ORG'), ('an estimated 30 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('Romere Pass', 'PERSON'), ('the Delta National Wildlife Refuge', 'EVENT'), ('the Delta Duck Facility', 'ORG'), ('Texas Petroleum Investment Company', 'ORG')]"
9947,2019-07-24,Hilcorp Homeplace Facility Discharge,"Port Sulphur, LA 70083, USA",29.41527778,-89.70444444,Oil,,,"On July 24, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division  received a report of a four BBL discharge of crude oil at the HILCORP Homeplace facility due to a malfunction in the salt water holding tank control panel which was filled with grease causing the overflow signal to fail.",2019,7,,"[('July 24, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('four', 'CARDINAL'), ('BBL', 'ORG'), ('the HILCORP Homeplace', 'FAC')]"
9939,2019-07-23,M/V Silver Lining Spill,"Hood Canal, WA",47.83935,-122.67795,Oil,,,"On July 23, 2019, The M/V Silver Lining partially sank about 1.3 miles southwest of the Hood Canal Bridge in Jefferson County, WA.  The vessel has 300 gals of diesel and 12 gals of oil aboard. Sheen has been observed coming from the vessel. OSRO and USCG are on site. USCG has requested information regarding environmental sensitivities at a potential salvage site.",2019,7,,"[('July 23, 2019', 'DATE'), ('The M/V Silver Lining', 'PRODUCT'), ('about 1.3 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Hood Canal Bridge', 'FAC'), ('Jefferson County', 'GPE'), ('WA', 'ORG'), ('300', 'CARDINAL'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sheen', 'ORG'), ('OSRO', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9938,2019-07-22,Construction Barge Potential Spill,"Long Beach Inner Harbor, CA",33.7425,-118.168889,Oil,Diesel,,"On July 22, 2019, the USCG Sector LA/Long Beach contacted the NOAA SSC to report a possible diesel spill from a construction barge in Long Beach?�s Inner Harbor.  The incident occurred at 0900 hrs and had a maximum potential volume of 200 gallons diesel.  Sector LA/LB requested trajectory support to aid in searching for any potentially oiled shoreline.",2019,7,[],"[('July 22, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector LA', 'ORG'), ('Long Beach', 'GPE'), ('Long Beach?�s Inner Harbor', 'FAC'), ('200 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('LA/LB', 'ORG')]"
9936,2019-07-18,Hilcorp Manilla Village Mud Lake Spill,LA,29.46944444,-89.96888889,Oil,,,"On July 18, 2019, the USCG notified the NOAA SSC of approximately 3 bbl Louisiana sweet crude discharged from the Hilcorp Manilla Village facility in Mud Lake (NRC report 1252432).  The source is secured. Approximately 2 bbls contained within hard and sorbent boom. Non recoverable sheen discovered by USCG and LOSCO on the eastern edge of Mud Lake on July 19.  USCG requested trajectory.",2019,7,,"[('July 18, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Louisiana', 'GPE'), ('Manilla Village', 'GPE'), ('Mud Lake', 'LOC'), ('NRC', 'ORG'), ('1252432', 'DATE'), ('Approximately 2', 'CARDINAL'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('LOSCO', 'ORG'), ('Mud Lake', 'LOC'), ('July 19', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9934,2019-07-16,Grand Isle Block 22 Sheen,LA,29.12277778,-89.96611111,Oil,,,"On July 16, 2019, the USCG received reports of a 6 mile by 0.75 mile sheen approximately 6 miles south of Grand Isle, LA.  Estimated quantity of release, as reported by the RP, is 5 barrels of Louisiana Sweet Crude. Release has been secured.   USCG requesting fate and trajectory.",2019,7,,"[('July 16, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('6 mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('0.75 mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('approximately 6 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Grand Isle', 'GPE'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('RP', 'ORG'), ('5 barrels', 'QUANTITY'), ('Louisiana Sweet Crude', 'FAC'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9937,2019-07-14,Vessel Mr. Claude discharge into unnamed bayou,"Buras, LA, USA",29.36513889,-89.57572222,Oil,,,"14 July 2019, near MM 22 on the Lower Mississippi River,  the 35-foot towing vessel Mr. Claude sank in an unnamed bayou in the vicinity of Mega Industries fleeting area. The vessel was reported to have 100 gallons of diesel onboard. Approximately 40x20 ft dull and rainbow sheen observed around the vessel.",2019,7,,"[('14 July 2019', 'DATE'), ('MM', 'GPE'), ('22', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Lower Mississippi River', 'LOC'), ('Claude', 'PERSON'), ('Mega Industries', 'ORG'), ('100 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('Approximately 40x20 ft', 'QUANTITY')]"
9935,2019-07-13,Hurricane Barry,"LA, USA",29.495188,-91.84680300000001,Other,,,Hurricane Barry made landfall at Marsh Island and Intracoastal City on the southern coast of Louisiana July 13th 2019 as a Category 1 hurricane. This Hotline was opened to capture incidents related to the hurricane.,2019,7,,"[('Hurricane Barry', 'PERSON'), ('Marsh Island', 'FAC'), ('Intracoastal City', 'GPE'), ('Louisiana', 'GPE'), ('July 13th 2019', 'DATE'), ('Category 1', 'FAC'), ('Hotline', 'ORG')]"
9932,2019-08-07,FV Alaganik Sinking,"Whittier, AK",60.778330000000004,-148.66722,Oil,diesel,5500.0,,2019,8,[],
9933,2019-05-07,"M/V Mary R, M/V Mary Fern, M/V Chattie Sue Smith","Mile Marker 21 IL River, Hardin, IL 62047, USA",39.153911,-90.615505,Oil,oil,4500.0,,2019,5,[],
9931,2019-01-07,M/V OKALOOSA Allison with two barges,"Gretna, LA 70053, USA",29.934133000000003,-90.05815799999999,Oil,Oil,0.0,"On July 1, 2019. the USCG Sector New Orleans IMD was notified of an allison that occurred between M/V Okaloosa and two barges. SSC notified. NOTIFICATION ONLY.",2019,1,[],"[('July 1, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans IMD', 'ORG'), ('M/V Okaloosa', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')]"
9929,2019-06-29,Olympic Tug and Barge Grounding,"Marginal Way S, Seattle, WA 98134, USA",47.58353136,-122.34501599999999,Oil,High Sulfur No.6 Fuel Oil,3360000.0,,2019,6,"[('No.6', 'CARDINAL')]",
9928,2019-06-28,Sulfuric Acid Release Train Derailment,"Sarnia, ON, Canada",42.9592,-82.4189,Chemical,Sulfuric Acid,,"On the morning of June 28, 2019, a train derailed in a tunnel connecting Port Huron, MI and Sarnia, ON Canada. There are reports of 25-50 gallons of sulfuric acid being released. The leaking car has a potential of 194,000 lbs. The train also is carrying 3000 gallons of diesel, no reports of fuel being released. USCG is requesting fate and reactivity of sulfuric acid.",2019,6,[],"[('the morning of June 28, 2019', 'TIME'), ('Port Huron', 'PERSON'), ('Sarnia', 'GPE'), ('Canada', 'GPE'), ('25-50 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('194,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('3000 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9930,2019-06-27,"1500GAL Diesel Fuel, Violet, LA","7701 E Judge Perez Dr, Violet, LA 70092, USA",29.87981111,-89.87440833,Oil,oil,1500.0,,2019,6,[],
9927,2019-06-26,Republic Steel Black River Sheen,"Lorain, OH",41.454167,-82.146389,Oil,OIl,,"On the morning of June 26, 2019, Republic Steel reported 50 - 200 gallons of an unknown petroleum product sheening in the Black River in Lorain, OH. OSRO is on site. Notification only, no products requested.",2019,6,[],"[('the morning of June 26, 2019', 'TIME'), ('Republic Steel', 'ORG'), ('50 - 200 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Black River', 'LOC'), ('Lorain', 'GPE'), ('OH', 'GPE'), ('OSRO', 'ORG')]"
9922,2019-06-25,"Poydras Energy Well Head , Main Pass Block 32","Main Pass, Mississippi River",29.46472222,-89.41361111,Oil,Oil,,"On June 13, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) was notified of a sheen originating from a well head in Main Pass 32 measuring 2 nautical miles by 30 feet, silver in color, via Forefront Emergency Management.",2019,6,[],"[('June 13, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('Main Pass 32', 'PRODUCT'), ('2 nautical miles by 30 feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('Forefront Emergency Management', 'ORG')]"
9926,2019-06-25,TPIC Jackup rig sheen,"Breton Sound, LA",29.48666667,-89.18833333,Oil,,,"On June 25, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division  received a notification about a light 2 mile sheen from an TPIC jackup rig. The sheen was in close proximity to Breton Island a known tern nesting site. USCG request an oil trajectory.",2019,6,,"[('June 25, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('about a light 2 mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('TPIC', 'GPE'), ('Breton Island', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9923,2019-06-25,Westlake Mercury Release,"Longview, WA",46.130720200000006,-122.9931879,Chemical,,,"On June 25, 2019, NOAA ERD was notified of an accidental flushing of mercury contaminated soil at a state designated hazardous waste site in Longview, WA. After a water main broke, uncontrolled water flushed through the contaminated site and entered the Columbia River. This was a notification only; no products or support are requested at this time.",2019,6,,"[('June 25, 2019', 'DATE'), ('NOAA ERD', 'ORG'), ('Longview', 'GPE'), ('WA', 'ORG'), ('the Columbia River', 'LOC')]"
9919,2019-06-24,Vessel Grounding M/V Timber Navigator,"Mississippi River, LA, USA",29.14833333,-89.25722222,Oil,,,"On June 23, 2019, the USCG notified NOAA SSC of the M/V Timber Navigator grounding at MM 0 of the Lower Mississippi River. The vessel is being held in position by its port anchor and tug assist vessel. The vessel is carrying approx 190 metric tons of various fuel and hydraulic oil. No current signs of discharge.",2019,6,,"[('June 23, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('MM 0 of', 'ORG'), ('the Lower Mississippi River', 'LOC'), ('190 metric tons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9918,2019-06-22,"Sheen report near Point Sur, CA","25 NM south of Point Sur, CA",35.89,-121.81,Oil,Possible oil,,"At 1630 hrs on 22-JUN-2019 the NOAA Ship R/V Bell M Shimada observed a sheen roughly 25 NM south of Point Sur, CA and forwarded photos and location to USCG Sector San Francisco and the NOAA SSC.  The USCG Duty Officer requested trajectory support to determine if the sheen might be related to a recent NOAA NESDIS Marine Pollution Surveillance Report (MPSR) issued in the vicinity on 20-JUN-2019.",2019,6,[],"[('1630', 'DATE'), ('NM', 'ORG'), ('Point Sur', 'GPE'), ('USCG Sector San Francisco', 'ORG'), ('NOAA NESDIS Marine Pollution Surveillance Report', 'ORG'), ('20-JUN-2019', 'CARDINAL')]"
9917,2019-06-21,Philadelphia Energy Solutions Refinery Fires and Explosions,"3100 Passyunk Ave, Philadelphia, PA 19153, USA",39.91445,-75.21782684,Chemical,Butane,,"On 21 June 2019, USCG Sector Delaware Bay notified the NOAA SSC of a fire, followed by several explosions at the Philadelphia Energy Solutions Refinery, located in SW Philadelphia. A shelter in place has been issued and several adjacent roadways and bridges have been closed. USCG has requested smoke plume modeling support.",2019,6,[],"[('21 June 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Delaware Bay', 'PERSON'), ('the Philadelphia Energy Solutions Refinery', 'ORG'), ('Philadelphia', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9920,2019-06-19,Linder Oil Atchafalaya Basin,"Pierre Part, LA",29.9686,-91.3413,Oil,,,"On June 18 2019. USCG MSU Morgan City conducted a survey of three Linder facilities. USCG has identified 37 drums, 10 five gallon buckets, 6 totes, and approximately 692 barrels of crude oil and produced water remaining on the three separate facilities. USCG requested resources at risk.",2019,6,,"[('June 18 2019', 'DATE'), ('Morgan City', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('37', 'CARDINAL'), ('10 five gallon', 'QUANTITY'), ('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('approximately 692 barrels', 'QUANTITY'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9916,2019-06-17,ALGOMA NIAGARA Grounding and Anchoring Near Pipeline,"Windsor, ON, Canada",42.28908,-83.09262,Oil,Propane/Ethane,19698.0,,2019,6,[],
9921,2019-06-14,Mystery Sheen  Viosca Knoll  900A,Gulf of Mexico,29.08444444,-88.70444444,Oil,oil sheen,,"On June 14, 2019, the Sector New Orleans IMD was notified of a mystery sheen passing through the Viosca Knoll 900 block measuring 2 nautical miles by 0.5 nautical miles, silver in color. The sheen was moving from West to East, and did not show any indication of a potential source, or that it was a continuous discharge.",2019,6,[],"[('June 14, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the Sector New Orleans IMD', 'ORG'), ('the Viosca Knoll', 'PRODUCT'), ('2 nautical miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('0.5 nautical miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('West to East', 'LOC')]"
9924,2019-08-06,Towing Vessel KAYTLIN MARIE / M/V CENTURY QUEEN Collision,Lower Mississippi River,29.991698,-90.41122299999999,Oil,Oil,8954.0,,2019,8,[],
9915,2019-06-06,F/V Alina,"Offshore Cameron Parish, LA,",29.44,-93.5885,Oil,Diesel,12000.0,,2019,6,[],
9925,2019-04-06,M/V SUN OF MAN 30 gallon diesel fuel discharge,"Venice Marina, Pier 9",29.24030556,-89.36361111,Oil,Diesel Fuel,30.0,"On June 4, 2019, the USCG IMD notified of a galley fire aboard the M/V SUN OF MAN while moored at pier 9 in Venice Marina. The Plaquemines Parish fire department responded and extinguished the fire. As a result of the fire, an estimated 30 gallons of diesel fuel were discharged overboard.",2019,4,[],"[('June 4, 2019', 'DATE'), ('9', 'CARDINAL'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('an estimated 30 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9913,2019-04-06,Mystery Sheen MP25,"Breton Sound, LA",29.5335,-89.41744444,Oil,,,"On June 4, 2019, the  USCG notified the NOAA SSC regarding a 1/4 mile mystery sheen in Breton Sound, LA. RP and status of release not yet known.",2019,4,,"[('June 4, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('1/4 mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('Breton Sound', 'GPE'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('RP', 'ORG')]"
9911,2019-03-06,Blue whale carcass,"Long Beach, CA",33.74789412,-118.218298,Other,Whale carcass,,"The NMFS Stranding Coordinator for CA contacted the NOAA SSC to report an 80??Blue whale carcass found within the Port of Long Beach on 03-JUN-2019.  No field necropsy is anticipated, so the carcass will likely be towed offshore on/about 04-JUN-2019.  NMFS requested a carcass drift estimate to aid in determining how far offshore to tow the carcass so it does not re-beach in the upcoming days.",2019,3,[],"[('the Port of Long Beach', 'FAC'), ('NMFS', 'ORG'), ('the upcoming days', 'DATE')]"
9912,2019-03-06,"Partially Submerged Barge and Landing Craft, Grindstone Island","Clayton, NY",44.297451,-76.08846700000001,Oil,,,"On June 3, 2019, USCG notified SSC about a partially submerged barge and landing craft on the north side of Grindstone Island, St. Lawrence River, Clayton, NY. Notification only, no products are being requested.",2019,3,,"[('June 3, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('SSC', 'ORG'), ('Grindstone Island', 'GPE'), ('St. Lawrence River', 'LOC'), ('Clayton', 'GPE'), ('NY', 'GPE')]"
9910,2019-05-31,Oil Spill MP315,Gulf of Mexico,29.08722222,-88.73361111,Oil,,,On May 31 2019 USCG Sector NOLA contacted the NOAA SSC regarding a crude oil mystery sheen related to a NESDIS report. Currently 20 bbl oil at the  surface. Discharge likely originating from recently plugged well. ROV and OSRO en route. NOAA providing trajectory and resources at risk.,2019,5,,"[('May 31 2019', 'DATE'), ('NESDIS', 'ORG'), ('20', 'CARDINAL'), ('ROV', 'ORG'), ('OSRO', 'ORG')]"
9909,2019-05-30,Ellwood Beach spill,"Goleta, CA",34.42489453,-119.907403,Oil,Crude oil,,"On 30-MAY-2019, the USCG Marine Safety Detachment Santa Barbara contacted the NOAA SSC regarding a 1-3 bbl spill of crude oil during a shoreside well abandonment operation on 28-MAY-2019.  USCG requested trajectory information to support shoreline assessment & cleanup activities, if needed.",2019,5,[],"[('30-MAY-2019', 'CARDINAL'), ('the USCG Marine Safety Detachment', 'ORG'), ('Santa Barbara', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('28-MAY-2019', 'CARDINAL'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9908,2019-05-30,"Fertilizer Release Pungo River, Belhaven, NC","Belhaven, NC, USA",35.58093744,-76.49285884,Other,Fertilizer,,"On 30 May 2019, USCG Sector North Carolina reached out to the NOAA SSC about a 1,000-5,000 gallon release of aqueous fertilizer from a holding tank into the Pungo River, in Belhaven, NC. USCG requested a trajectory.",2019,5,[],"[('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('May 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG Sector North Carolina', 'ORG'), ('1,000-5,000 gallon', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Pungo River', 'LOC'), ('Belhaven', 'GPE'), ('NC', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9907,2019-05-26,Bowley Cap Crude Oil Spill,"Cut Off, LA , USA",29.47138889,-90.38277778,Oil,,,"On May 26, 2019, the USCG notified the New Orleans SSC of 50bbl crude oil spill into the marsh and adjacent waterway.  USCG requested consultation support for threatened and endangered species in the area.",2019,5,,"[('May 26, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('the New Orleans', 'LOC'), ('50bbl', 'CARDINAL'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9914,2019-05-25,"Hydrogen Pipeline Possibly Struck; Bulk Carrier BULK PATRIOT, Potential only",Mississippi River,30.04933333,-90.51613889,Other,,,"On May 25, 2019, USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) received notification that the M/V BULK PATRIOT a bulk carrier suffered a lost propulsion on the Mississippi River. While dropping anchor, the STBD anchor brake failed to function causing the chain to pay out and did not stop until the end of the chain. Sector New Orleans knew there is a pipeline in the vicinity of the anchor dragging and began to investigate to ensure there was no damage to any pipelines. IMD will continue to monitor the situation provide updates as necessary.",2019,5,,"[('May 25, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('the M/V BULK', 'PRODUCT'), ('the Mississippi River', 'LOC'), ('STBD', 'ORG'), ('New Orleans', 'GPE'), ('IMD', 'ORG')]"
9906,2019-05-23,Diammonium Phosphate Barges,"Webbers Falls, OK",35.553641999999996,-95.169527,Chemical,diammonium phosphate DAP,,"On May 23, 2019, the NOAA SSC was notified that two loaded fertilizer barges (DAP) broke free from the Oakley Terminal along the Arkansas River due to flooding in eastern Oklahoma.  The barges struck and then sank at the  Webbers Falls Lock and Dam 16 at approximately 12 PM local time.  The USCG is requesting fate and behavior of the spilled material.",2019,5,"[('DAP', 'ORG')]","[('May 23, 2019', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('DAP', 'ORG'), ('the Oakley Terminal', 'ORG'), ('the Arkansas River', 'LOC'), ('Oklahoma', 'GPE'), ('16', 'CARDINAL'), ('approximately 12 PM local time', 'TIME'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9905,2019-05-21,JOSEPH M. CUDAHY (RULET),Florida,25.0228,-82.7563,Oil,,,"On May 7, 1942, the tanker Joseph M. Cudahy, was torpedoed and sunk during World War II northwest of Key West, Florida. The wreck has been identified as a potential pollution threat in NOAA RULET (Response to Undersea Legacy Environmental Threats). The USCG has requested NOAA review the trajectory analyses and resources at risk information contained in the original RULET report for the vessel to  support response planning for the wreck.",2019,5,,"[('May 7, 1942', 'DATE'), ('Joseph M. Cudahy', 'PERSON'), ('World War II', 'EVENT'), ('Key West', 'GPE'), ('Florida', 'GPE'), ('NOAA', 'GPE'), ('Undersea Legacy Environmental Threats', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('NOAA', 'ORG'), ('RULET', 'ORG')]"
9904,2019-05-18,"Chlorine Plant Fire, Kearny, NJ","55 Jacobus Ave, Kearny, NJ 07032, USA",40.735312,-74.11340200000001,Chemical,Granular Chlorine,,"At 0100 hours on 18 May 2019, USCG Sector New York contacted the NOAA SSC about a fire at the Alden Leads Chemical Plant, Kearny, New Jersey,  a facility that produces and stores chlorine. USCG requested a smoke plume model.",2019,5,[],"[('0100 hours', 'TIME'), ('18 May 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG Sector New York', 'ORG'), ('the Alden Leads Chemical Plant', 'FAC'), ('Kearny', 'GPE'), ('New Jersey', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9903,2019-05-16,Sulfur dioxide release,"Shell Refinery, Martinez, CA",38.01881826,-122.11685659999999,Chemical,Sulfur dioxide,,"On May 16, 2019, the USCG Sector San Francisco contacted their NOAA SSC to report an airborne release of 500 lbs Sulfur Dioxide from a flare stack at the Shell Refinery in Martinez, CA.  USCG requested an estimate of potential airborne concentrations downwind of the release and how far concentrations might exceed levels of concern.",2019,5,[],"[('May 16, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector San Francisco', 'ORG'), ('500', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Shell Refinery', 'FAC'), ('Martinez', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9901,2019-05-15,Gray whale carcass,"Pacifica, CA",37.59804809,-122.51103400000001,Other,Whale carcass,,"On 15-MAY-2019, NMFS Stranding Network staff contacted the NOAA SSC regarding a 40??gray whale carcass that had washed ashore near Pacifica, CA the day before.  No field necropsy is anticipated, so the carcass may be towed offshore on 15 or 16-MAY.  NMFS requested a carcass drift estimate to aid in determining how far offshore to tow the carcass so it does not re-beach in the upcoming days.",2019,5,[],"[('15-MAY-2019', 'CARDINAL'), ('NMFS Stranding Network', 'ORG'), ('40??gray', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pacifica', 'GPE'), ('the day before', 'DATE'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('16-MAY', 'DATE'), ('NMFS', 'ORG'), ('the upcoming days', 'DATE')]"
9902,2019-05-15,Gray whale carcass,"Carlsbad, CA",33.15479859,-117.3516655,Other,Whale carcass,,"The NMFS Stranding Coordinator for CA contacted the NOAA SSC to report a 25-30??Gray whale carcass that had come ashore near Carlsbad, CA on 15-MAY-2019.  No field necropsy is anticipated, so the carcass may be towed offshore on/about 16-MAY.  NMFS requested a carcass drift estimate to aid in determining how far offshore to tow the carcass so it does not re-beach in the upcoming days.",2019,5,[],"[('25-30??Gray', 'QUANTITY'), ('Carlsbad', 'GPE'), ('CA', 'ORG'), ('15-MAY-2019', 'CARDINAL'), ('NMFS', 'ORG'), ('the upcoming days', 'DATE')]"
9900,2019-10-05,"Bayport Channel Collision, Houston Ship Canal near Bayport, TX","Houston Ship Channel, TX, USA",29.630353399999997,-94.97758482,Oil,Reformate (gasoline blending stock),1050000.0,,2019,10,[],
9899,2019-09-05,"Smith Island Grounding, near Smith Island, WA","Near Smith Island, WA",48.31872222,-122.851,Oil,,,"On May 09, 2019, the USCG Sector Puget Sound contacted NOAA ERD to report the grounding of a Canadian whale-watching vessel, the 4 Ever Wild, near Smith Island, WA. The maximum potential discharge was reported as 264 gallons of diesel fuel. No spill has occurred at this time. Resources at Risk were requested.",2019,9,,"[('May 09, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector Puget Sound', 'LAW'), ('NOAA ERD', 'ORG'), ('Canadian', 'NORP'), ('4', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ever Wild', 'LOC'), ('Smith Island', 'GPE'), ('WA', 'ORG'), ('264 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9898,2019-08-05,Sunken Crane Barge - Offshore Freeport,"Offshore Freeport, TX",28.35,-95.48,Oil,Diesel,150.0,,2019,8,[],
9896,2019-07-05,FV Masonic Grounding,"Spanish Islands, Alaska",55.970278,-134.12305600000002,Oil,diesel,2000.0,,2019,7,[],
9897,2019-07-05,Gray whale carcass,"Oxnard, CA",34.15733025,-119.227007,Other,Whale carcass,,"On 07-MAY-2019, NMFS Stranding Network Coordinator contacted their NOAA SSC regarding a gray whale carcass that had washed ashore near Channel Islands Harbor in Ventura County, CA.  NMFS requested a carcass drift estimate to aid in determining how far offshore to tow the carcass so it does not re-beach in the upcoming days.",2019,7,[],"[('Channel Islands Harbor', 'LOC'), ('Ventura County', 'GPE'), ('CA', 'GPE'), ('NMFS', 'ORG'), ('the upcoming days', 'DATE')]"
9894,2019-02-05,FV Ann Kathleen,"Bandon, OR",42.9765,-124.47116670000001,Oil,,,"On May 2, 2019, the  USCG responded to a commercial fishing vessel, Ann Kathleen, on fire and aground about 9 nautical miles south of the  Coquille River Bar in southern Oregon at location 42°58'35.4""N, 124°28'16.2""W. The vessel has an estimated 2000 gallons of diesel aboard. Oil discharge has not been observed nor reported.",2019,2,,"[('May 2, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Ann Kathleen', 'PERSON'), ('9', 'CARDINAL'), ('Coquille River Bar', 'FAC'), ('Oregon', 'GPE'), ('42°58\'35.4""N', 'CARDINAL'), ('an estimated 2000 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9895,2019-02-05,ITV Cindy R,"Mile Marker 8, Harvey Locks, Gulf Intercoastal Waterway, LA",29.856867600000005,-90.06493459999999,Oil,oil,,"On MAY 2, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans IMD received a report that T/V Cindy R owned and operated by Gulf South Marine Enterprises, LLC sank in the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway West mile marker 8 near Harvey Locks. Unknown amount was discharged into the waterway.",2019,2,[],"[('MAY 2, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans IMD', 'ORG'), ('T/V Cindy R', 'ORG'), ('Gulf South Marine Enterprises', 'ORG'), ('LLC', 'ORG'), ('the Gulf Intracoastal Waterway', 'FAC'), ('West mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('8', 'CARDINAL'), ('Harvey Locks', 'LOC')]"
9893,2019-04-29,Gray whale carcass,"Port of LA/Long Beach, CA",33.72091302,-118.2180405,Other,Whale carcass,,"On April 29, 2019, the NMFS Stranding Network Coordinator contacted their NOAA SSC regarding a gray whale carcass that had washed ashore at the Port of LA/Long Beach.  NMFS requested a carcass drift estimate to aid in determining how far offshore to tow the carcass so it does not re-beach in the upcoming days.",2019,4,[],"[('April 29, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the Port of LA/Long Beach', 'FAC'), ('NMFS', 'ORG'), ('the upcoming days', 'DATE')]"
9891,2019-04-25,ISTOP Anomaly Report,"Kayak Island, Alaska",58.74225,-144.67275,Oil,unknown,,"On 25-Apr-2019,  USCG MSU Valdez received an ISTOP (Integrated satellite tracking of pollution) report of a possible oil spill and requested NOAA analysis to determine if the possible oil will impact shoreline.",2019,4,[],[]
9892,2019-04-25,Womens Bay Abandoned Barge,"Kodiak, AK",57.699130000000004,-152.52545,Oil,diesel,1200.0,,2019,4,[],
9890,2019-04-23,Mystery Sheen @ South Pass 60,South Pass Block 60,29.06194444,-88.94222222,Oil,,,"On April 23, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) called the SSC to request satellite imagery for a mystery sheen at South Pass 60.  The mystery sheen was discovered during an USCG overflight to West Delta block 79A and NRC report # 1243536 was generated.",2019,4,,"[('April 23, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('SSC', 'ORG'), ('South Pass 60', 'EVENT'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('West Delta', 'LOC'), ('79A', 'CARDINAL'), ('NRC', 'ORG'), ('1243536', 'DATE')]"
9888,2019-04-22,Unknown Sheen West Delta Block 79A,West Delta Block 79A,28.971390000000003,-89.51472,Oil,,,"On April 22, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans called the SSC about an unknown sheen. Sheen color is described as 60% slightly colored, 30% silvery, and 10% barely visible. Sheen length is 4NM long and 50 feet wide. USCG requested a fate and trajectory and also 72 hours monitoring from NESDIS.",2019,4,,"[('April 22, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans', 'ORG'), ('SSC', 'ORG'), ('Sheen', 'ORG'), ('60%', 'PERCENT'), ('30%', 'PERCENT'), ('10%', 'PERCENT'), ('Sheen', 'ORG'), ('4NM', 'CARDINAL'), ('50 feet', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('72 hours', 'TIME'), ('NESDIS', 'ORG')]"
9887,2019-04-21,TV Aqua Loyalty,Mississippi Sound,30.22,-88.561598,Oil,Colombian crude API 22.6,21000000.0,,2019,4,"[('Colombian', 'NORP')]",
9886,2019-04-19,M/V Never Say Never sunk,"Off Ano Nuevo, CA",37.07,-122.37,Oil,"Diesel, marine debris",1200.0,,2019,4,[],
9889,2019-04-18,Possible seep activity,"Off Point Arguello, CA",34.58799746,-120.74111940000002,Oil,Crude oil,,"On 18-APR-2019, USCG Marine Safety Detachment (MSD) Santa Barbara contacted their NOAA SSC to discuss recent oil sheen observations NW of Santa Barbara Channel.  USCG has requested potential remote sensing support.  This Hotline is being created to capture remote sensing information, as needed.",2019,4,[],"[('18-APR-2019', 'CARDINAL'), ('USCG Marine Safety Detachment', 'ORG'), ('MSD', 'ORG'), ('Santa Barbara', 'GPE'), ('Santa Barbara Channel', 'GPE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Hotline', 'ORG')]"
9885,2019-04-16,Gray whale carcass,"Pacifica, CA 94044, USA",37.64876219,-122.4945116,Other,Whale,,"In the evening of 16-APR-2019, NMFS Stranding Network staff contacted their NOAA SSC regarding a gray whale carcass that had washed ashore near Pacifica, CA.  A field necropsy is scheduled for 17-APR-2019, after which the carcass would be towed offshore.  NMFS requested a carcass drift estimate to aid in determining how far offshore to tow the carcass so it does not re-beach in the upcoming days.",2019,4,[],"[('the evening', 'TIME'), ('NMFS Stranding Network', 'ORG'), ('Pacifica', 'GPE'), ('CA', 'GPE'), ('17-APR-2019', 'CARDINAL'), ('NMFS', 'ORG'), ('the upcoming days', 'DATE')]"
9884,2019-04-15,T/V Dejeanne Maria,"Venice, LA 70091, USA",29.1525,-89.245,Oil,Diesel/Lube Oil,,"On April 15, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) received a report that Towing Vessel Dejeanne Maria hit a submerged dredge pipe and sank near the Mississippi River in Pass A Loutre with ~ 7000 gallons of diesel/lube oil onboard. The discharged amount into the waterways is unknown.",2019,4,[],"[('April 15, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('Vessel Dejeanne Maria', 'PERSON'), ('the Mississippi River', 'LOC'), ('7000 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9883,2019-04-14,ITV Buckles MO River,"Slater, MO 65349, USA",39.1205,-92.94266667,Oil,diesel,8000.0,,2019,4,[],
9882,2019-12-04,S/V Morena,"Mona Island , Puerto Rico",18.11,-67.87,Oil,,,"On April 7, 2019, a 45 foot fiberglass catamaran sailing vessel ran aground at Mona Island Puerto Rico. The vessel has 50 gallons of diesel on board. The vessel is resting on coral including Staghorn coral. The USCG plans to address the pollution threat and work with Puerto Rico authorities to remove the vessel.",2019,12,,"[('April 7, 2019', 'DATE'), ('45 foot', 'QUANTITY'), ('Mona Island Puerto Rico', 'FAC'), ('50 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Puerto Rico', 'GPE')]"
9881,2019-10-04,Oceanographic Buoy Adrift,"Coos Bay, Oregon",43.29861111,-124.53194440000001,Other,,,"On April 10, 2019, the NOAA Marine Debris Program was notified that a 14-foot long (1500 lbs) oceanographic buoy detached from its mooring on Friday, April 5 at location 43° 17' 55""N, 124° 31' 55""W (7 miles west of Cape Arago, Oregon). A trajectory was requested.",2019,10,,"[('April 10, 2019', 'DATE'), ('NOAA Marine Debris Program', 'ORG'), ('Friday, April 5', 'DATE'), ('7 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Cape Arago', 'GPE'), ('Oregon', 'GPE')]"
9880,2019-10-04,TPIC Crude Oil Discharge Delta Duck,"1, LA, USA",29.24555556,-89.19916667,Oil,,,"On April 10, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) notied the NOAA SSC that the TPIC Delta Duck Facility had a 6 inch transfer line ball valve fail. TPIC initially reported 3 bbl of crude oil discharged into Delta National Wildlife Refuge's unnamed canal surrounding the facility.",2019,10,,"[('April 10, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('6 inch', 'QUANTITY'), ('3 bbl', 'QUANTITY'), (""Delta National Wildlife Refuge's"", 'LOC')]"
9877,2019-03-04,Hilcorp CF#6 Facility,"Louisiana, USA",29.58583333,-90.05944444,Oil,,,"On March 24, 2019, the USCG  Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) received NRC Report #1240899 reporting a discharge of an estimated 3bbls of crude oil into an unnamed canal and muddy marsh area, tributary to the Dupre Cut/Barataria Bay Waterway, in Jefferson Parish, LA.  Hilcorp personnel secured the discharge. IMD personnel are on scene at the incident location to conduct an onsite assessment, to determine any further environmental impact  to ensure proper clean up and response actions and will continue to work with Hilcorp to monitor the situation.",2019,3,,"[('March 24, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('NRC Report', 'ORG'), ('1240899', 'MONEY'), ('an estimated 3bbls', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Dupre Cut/', 'ORG'), ('Jefferson Parish', 'GPE'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('Hilcorp', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('Hilcorp', 'ORG')]"
9875,2019-03-04,LOBO Tank Battery 1 Leak,"Venice, LA",29.32194444,-89.29111111,Oil,,,"On April 1, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) notified the NOAA SSC that the LOBO Operation Inc. Tank Battery 1 in Venice, LA, had an 8 inch transfer line fail while they were shut-in. USCG estimated approximately 10 bbl of crude oil was spilled into unnamed canal. IMD will continue to work with responsible party to monitor situation.",2019,3,,"[('April 1, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('the LOBO Operation Inc. Tank', 'ORG'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('8 inch', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('approximately 10', 'CARDINAL'), ('IMD', 'ORG')]"
9876,2019-03-04,Partially Submerged Recreational Vessel at JSBB Marina,"Mandeville, LA",30.353,-90.051,Oil,Unknown ( Possibly dirty motor oil),1.0,"On March 24, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans notified the NOAA SSC of a discharge from a partially submerged, 36-ft recreational vessel, named MISS JILLY, at The JSBB Marina, in St. Tammany Parish, LA.  USCG IMD will continue to work the marina owner/operator to monitor the situation and provide updates as necessary.",2019,3,[],"[('March 24, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans', 'ORG'), ('36-ft', 'CARDINAL'), ('JILLY', 'PERSON'), ('The JSBB Marina', 'LOC'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('USCG IMD', 'ORG')]"
9878,2019-03-04,Unknown Oil and Source at Venice Marina,"Marina Rd, Venice, LA",29.23856389,-89.36359167,Oil,Motor Oil,,"On March 22, 2019, the  US Coast Guard Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) received NRC Report # 1240778 reporting a mystery spill at the Venice Marina, in Plaquemines Parish, LA. The discharged product is reported to be used  motor oil. USCG personnel are en route to the incident location to conduct on site assessment and investigation as to the potential source and/or cause of the discharge.",2019,3,[],"[('March 22, 2019', 'DATE'), ('US Coast Guard Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('NRC Report', 'ORG'), ('1240778', 'MONEY'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Plaquemines Parish', 'GPE'), ('LA', 'GPE')]"
9873,2019-01-04,Mystery Sheen Main Pass 63,Gulf of Mexico,29.33416667,-88.99361111,Oil,,,"On April 1, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans contacted the NOAA SSC regarding a 4nm x 2nm silvery mystery sheen originally identified on March 29 2019.  USCG requested assistance identifying this sheen in past and future NESDIS Satellite reports.",2019,1,,"[('April 1, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans', 'ORG'), ('4nm x 2nm', 'QUANTITY'), ('March 29 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('NESDIS Satellite', 'ORG')]"
9872,2019-03-28,"Dublin Express Oil Spill, Staten Island, New York","Arthur Kill, Staten Island, NY",40.55711297,-74.21539309,Oil,#6 bunker fuel,100000.0,,2019,3,[],
9870,2019-03-19,Seattle Slew Diesel Spill Mississippi River,"Mississippi River mm55, LA 70040, USA",29.61017769,-89.88078117,Oil,,,"On March 19, 2018, the USCG Sector NOLA contacted the SSC regarding a sunken tug at mm 55 in the Mississippi River.  Efforts are focused on one missing person but a 3 mile sheen was reported and USCG requested an initial trajectory for a worst case discharge of 9k gal of diesel.",2019,3,,"[('March 19, 2018', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('mm 55', 'FAC'), ('the Mississippi River', 'LOC'), ('3 mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('9k gal', 'QUANTITY')]"
9867,2019-03-18,"Coal Washup Cape Charles, VA","Cape Charles, VA",37.2539427,-76.01989746,Other,Coal,,"The NOAA SSC received a notification from USCG Sector Hampton Roads on 18 March, 2019 about an estimated four miles of coal that has washed ashore in Chesapeake Bay  adjacent to Cape Charles, VA on the Eastern Shore.  Coal was first observed coming ashore on 14 March. USCG is in the process of establishing a Unified Command to address the situation. USCG requested NOAA to provide clean-up recommendations and to identify possible resources at risk.",2019,3,[],"[('18 March, 2019', 'DATE'), ('about an estimated four miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Chesapeake Bay', 'LOC'), ('Cape Charles', 'PERSON'), ('VA', 'GPE'), ('the Eastern Shore', 'LOC'), ('14 March', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Unified Command', 'ORG')]"
9868,2019-03-18,"M/V La Pinta - Miami, FL",Port of Miami Anchorage,25.75645465,-80.11084557,Oil,,,"On March 18, 2019,  the USCG Sector Miami/RRT contacted the NOAA SSC to discuss response options for a Haitian freighter at the Port of Miami anchorage. The vessel has 4500 gallons of diesel on board, some other various hazmat items not yet identified, and is taking on sea water.  Weather and trajectory products requested but vessel is not leaking fuel oil at this time.",2019,3,,"[('March 18, 2019', 'DATE'), ('Haitian', 'NORP'), ('the Port of Miami', 'FAC'), ('4500 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('Weather', 'PERSON'), ('trajectory', 'CARDINAL')]"
9866,2019-03-17,"ITC Tank Fire, Deer Park, TX","1942 Independence Parkway, Deer Park, TX",29.73277778,-95.09111111,Oil,naptha,3360000.0,,2019,3,[],
9865,2019-03-16,Buskin River Diesel Spill,"Kodiak, AK",57.75778969,-152.5156246,Oil,diesel,1400.0,,2019,3,[],
9864,2019-03-16,"PAC ATHENA Ferrosilicon Cargo, Port of Morehead City, NC","Beaufort, NC",34.72885975,-76.67536925,Chemical,Ferrosilicon,,"On March 16, 2019, USCG Sector North Carolina contacted the NOAA SSC about a cargo vessel that docked at the Port of Morehead City containing a cargo of ferrosilicon. USCG requested technical information about the chemical, associated human health and environmental risks and recommended safety measures. There has not been any chemical release.",2019,3,[],"[('March 16, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG Sector North Carolina', 'ORG'), ('the Port of Morehead City', 'FAC'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9863,2019-10-03,F/V ALL MY JOY,"Fishers Island, NY",41.26833333,-72.025,Oil,,,"On March 10, 2019, the fishing vessel ALL MY JOY capsized after taking on water and notifying the Sector Long Island Sound (all souls rescued).  The vessel continued to float upside down and finally grounded about 3/4 miles off Fishers Island, NY. with 2000 gallons of diesel on-board.  Only light sheen was observed, the remaining oil still in the tanks.  USCG is planning an oil removal and salvage.",2019,10,,"[('March 10, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the Sector Long Island Sound', 'FAC'), ('about 3/4 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Fishers Island', 'LOC'), ('NY', 'GPE'), ('2000 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9862,2019-07-03,Sunken Tug Mississippi River,"LaPlace, LA",30.03402771,-90.47052383,Oil,,,"On March 7, 2019, the USCG notified the NOLA SSC of a potential release from a tug boat sunken along the left descending bank at MM 132 near La Place, LA.  The vessel has a worst case potential discharge of 9,500 gallons diesel.  A slight sheen reported.  The USCG requested an oil trajectory.",2019,7,,"[('March 7, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('MM 132', 'ORG'), ('La Place', 'GPE'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('9,500 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9861,2019-02-28,Olympia Brewery Transformer Spill,"Tumwater, WA",47.01163024,-122.90448190000001,Oil,,,"February 28, 2019 - An unknown quantity of transformer oil was released into the Deschutes River from the site of the old Olympia Brewery in Tumwater, Washington. The maximum capacity of the transformer was 700 gallons. The spill is now controlled and the cause of release is under investigation.",2019,2,,"[('February 28, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the Deschutes River', 'LOC'), ('Olympia Brewery', 'PERSON'), ('Tumwater', 'GPE'), ('Washington', 'GPE'), ('700 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9859,2019-02-27,FV Arctic Storm,"Bering Sea, Alaska",56.196467000000005,-162.55973,Oil,hydraulic oil,1081.0,,2019,2,[],
9858,2019-02-27,Guardian Plane Search,"Admiralty Island, Alaska",56.99501028,-134.4671631,Other,,,"On 29-Jan-2019, at 1810, a Guardian medical flight went down south of Admiralty Island.  Global Salvage is on scene to recover the plane and black box. They are requesting a NWS Spot Forecast for dive operations.",2019,2,,"[('29-Jan-2019', 'DATE'), ('1810', 'DATE'), ('Guardian', 'ORG'), ('Admiralty Island', 'LOC')]"
9860,2019-02-27,LC Don Quixote,"Kodiak Island, Alaska",57.791669999999996,-153.93083000000001,Oil,diesel,800.0,,2019,2,[],
9857,2019-02-25,Sump Pump Discharge into Lake St. Clair,"St Clair Shores, MI",42.478953000000004,-82.88062099999999,Oil,Oil,2500.0,,2019,2,[],
9856,2019-02-23,"Cargo Plane Crash, Trinity Bay,TX","Anahuac, TX 77514, USA",29.76333333,-94.715,Oil,JP-5 (Heavy Kerosene,24000.0,,2019,2,[],
9855,2019-02-23,FV Kaia,"Unimak Island, Alaska",54.7961,-164.5847,Oil,diesel,4000.0,,2019,2,[],
9854,2019-02-17,M/V St Clair Vessel Fire Maumee River,"Toledo, OH",41.699087,-83.45110799999999,Oil,Fuel Oil,69000.0,,2019,2,[],
9852,2019-02-15,FV Pacific 1,"Unalaska Island, Alaska",53.5099,-167.187,Oil,diesel,6000.0,,2019,2,[],
9853,2019-02-15,West Cameron 398 Unknown Sheen,Offshore Gulf of Mexico,28.94933333,-93.55233333,Oil,Unknown Sheen,,"On February 15, 2019, MSU Port Arthur contacted ERD to request trajectory for sheen located approximately 60 miles offshore.  Sheen reported as 16 ft x 2 miles rainbow in NRC#1237739.  AIRSTA Houston launched helo, unable to reach site due to weather.  Local assets confirmed presence of sheen, but located no apparent source. We do not expect shoreline impacts based on the current observations.",2019,2,[],"[('February 15, 2019', 'DATE'), ('MSU Port Arthur', 'ORG'), ('ERD', 'ORG'), ('trajectory', 'CARDINAL'), ('sheen', 'ORG'), ('approximately 60 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Sheen', 'ORG'), ('16 ft x 2 miles rainbow', 'QUANTITY'), ('NRC#1237739', 'CARDINAL')]"
9851,2019-02-13,Lindsey Lake Tanker Spill,"Vietnam Veterans Memorial Highway, Cascade Locks, OR 97014, USA",45.68741528,-121.712755,Oil,Diesel Fuel,4000.0,,2019,2,[],
9849,2019-10-02,"Trawler Aground Swinomish Channel, Puget Sound","North end of Swinomish Channel, Anacortes, WA",48.46094167,-122.5170636,Oil,,,"On the afternoon of February 10th, 2019, NW SSC was notified by USCG Sector Puget Sound of a 50' trawler which ran aground at the northern end of the Swinomish Channel near Padilla Bay.  Vessel appears to be intact at this time as there is no reported sheen.  USCG and Swinomish Tribe will attempt to get a party aboard to sound the vessel to determine if any product is still aboard.  Swinomish tribe is attempting to contact the owner.  USCG will continue to monitor the site for any signs of spillage.",2019,10,,"[('the afternoon of February 10th, 2019', 'TIME'), ('the Swinomish Channel', 'ORG'), ('Padilla Bay', 'LOC'), ('Vessel', 'PRODUCT'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('Swinomish Tribe', 'ORG'), ('Swinomish', 'NORP'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9848,2019-09-02,T/V Ed McLaughlin Sinking Ohio River,"Cheshire, OH",38.916055,-82.124537,Oil,Diesel,8000.0,,2019,9,[],
9847,2019-06-02,FV Big John Vessel Grounding,"Frisco, NC, USA",35.22469078,-75.63915253,Oil,deisel fuel,800.0,,2019,6,[],
9845,2019-05-02,Mystery Sheen - Cape Lookout State Park,Oregon,45.34321758,-123.97882460000001,Oil,,,"February 05, 2019 - At 1115 PST NOAA ERD was contacted by USCG Sector Columbia River responding to a mystery sheen reported at Cape Lookout State Park, Oregon.   Emulsified product was observed in the surf zone and on the beach. No products are being requested at this time.",2019,5,,"[('February 05, 2019 -', 'DATE'), ('1115', 'DATE'), ('USCG Sector Columbia River', 'ORG'), ('Cape Lookout State Park', 'FAC'), ('Oregon', 'GPE')]"
9850,2019-03-02,Hobby Airport JP-8 Discharge,"7714 Airport Blvd, Houston, TX 77061, USA",29.655,-95.27666667,Oil,JP-8,64000.0,,2019,3,[],
9844,2019-02-02,Northlake Way Bunker C Seepage,"Seattle, WA",47.64755194,-122.34050990000001,Oil,,,"February 02, 2019, 1015 PST - NOAA ERD was contacted by USCG Sector Puget Sound responding to Bunker C leaching into North Lake Union as a result of a burst water main and subsequent flushing of previously contaminated soil. The source (water leak) is secured and initial estimates of total volume of Bunker C entering the lake was said to be around 20-30 gallons. No products are requested.",2019,2,,"[('February 02, 2019', 'DATE'), ('1015', 'DATE'), ('PST', 'ORG'), ('Bunker C', 'ORG'), ('North Lake Union', 'GPE'), ('Bunker C', 'ORG'), ('20-30 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9843,2019-01-23,Tarballs Observed - Point Reyes National Seashore,"Inverness, CA.",38.12159327,-122.95761110000001,Oil,Oil,,"On January 23, 2019, the USCG District 11 notified OR&R of reported mystery tarballs at two locations on the Point Reyes National Seashore that washed up following a storm.",2019,1,[],"[('January 23, 2019', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('OR&R', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Point Reyes National Seashore', 'ORG')]"
9841,2019-01-17,Kirby 10227,"Carlton Township, AR, USA",33.30527778,-91.16472222,Chemical,,,"On January 17, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans called the NOAA SSC regarding a barge that ran aground on the left descending bank in the Mississippi river. The barge was carrying 10,000 lbs  of Dichloromethane at the time of accident. There has been no sign of discharge.",2019,1,,"[('January 17, 2019', 'DATE'), ('New Orleans', 'GPE'), ('Mississippi', 'GPE'), ('10,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dichloromethane', 'GPE')]"
9842,2019-01-17,Mystery Sheen in Gulf of Mexico,"Offshore, Mississippi River Delta",28.98833333,-88.67833333,Oil,Unknown,,On 17JAN19 at 1515 USCG Sector New Orleans contacted SSC regarding a mystery rainbow sheen 5 miles by 500 ft heading from the West to the East. The sheen was reported at 1301 by a privately owned aircraft. USCG is currently trying to ascertain the origins of the spill.,2019,1,[],"[('17JAN19', 'DATE'), ('New Orleans', 'GPE'), ('5 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('500', 'CARDINAL'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('East', 'LOC'), ('1301', 'DATE'), ('USCG', 'ORG')]"
9840,2019-01-16,"South Pass, Block 23","Venice, LA",29.03138889,-89.24972222,Oil,Crude Oil,50.0,"On January 16, 2019, the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division (IMD) was notified that an estimated 50 gallons of crude oil was discharged near the Pass A Loutre Wildlife Management Area, in Plaquemines Parish, LA. The discharge was reportedly from a facility owned and operated by Whitney Oil & Gas, LLC. The USCG contacted the NOAA Scientific Support Coordinator (SSC) to request satellite imagery of the discharge location to confirm sheen size and trajectory, and NOAA Satellite Analysts reported no satellite imagery was available in the discharge location. An overflight is scheduled to be conducted over the incident location in the morning to confirm sheen sighting and plan recovery product.",2019,1,[],"[('January 16, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the USCG Sector New Orleans Incident Management Division', 'ORG'), ('IMD', 'ORG'), ('an estimated 50 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('the Pass A Loutre Wildlife Management Area', 'FAC'), ('LA', 'GPE'), ('Whitney Oil & Gas', 'ORG'), ('LLC', 'ORG'), ('USCG', 'ORG'), ('the NOAA Scientific Support Coordinator', 'ORG'), ('NOAA Satellite Analysts', 'ORG'), ('the morning', 'TIME'), ('confirm sheen sighting', 'ORG')]"
9839,2019-08-01,Hilcorp CF-6,"Lafitte, LA.",29.66055556,-90.10833333,Oil,Crude Oil,252.0,,2019,8,[],
9838,2019-07-01,F/V A.E. CLIFFORD Sinking,"Superior, WI",46.738341999999996,-92.098947,Oil,,,"On Friday January 4th, 2019 the F/V A. E. CLIFFORD was taking on water at the Hughitt Slip Pier in Superior, WI. Superior Fire Department arrived on-scene, verified there were no persons on board, and began attempting to de-water the vessel. MSU Duluth's Duty Prevention Officer and pollution responder arrived on-scene, reported no visible signs of pollution in the water, however the smell of diesel and oil was present on the vessel. Potential of 200 gallons.",2019,7,,"[('Friday January 4th, 2019', 'DATE'), ('the Hughitt Slip Pier in Superior', 'FAC'), ('WI', 'PERSON'), ('Superior Fire Department', 'ORG'), (""MSU Duluth's"", 'ORG'), ('200 gallons', 'QUANTITY')]"
9846,2019-04-01,F/V Mistress,"Block Island, RI",41.13,-71.49833333,Oil,,,"On January 1, 2019 the F/V MISTRESS was underway in the vicinity of Block Island, Rhode Island when the vessel took on water with three people aboard. When the dewatering pumps were unable to keep up, the boat capsized with two crewmembers aboard. These two crew are missing.  The F/V CAPT BLIGH rescued the third crewman from the life raft. The NOAA SSC was contacted asked to help coordinate with the Navigational Response Team.",2019,4,,"[('January 1, 2019', 'DATE'), ('Block Island', 'GPE'), ('Rhode Island', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('The F/V CAPT BLIGH', 'PRODUCT'), ('third', 'ORDINAL'), ('the Navigational Response Team', 'ORG')]"
9837,2018-12-18,"Diesel Discharge, Lower Mississippi River MM125","Mississippi River, Hahnville, LA , USA",29.9825,-90.40138889,Oil,Diesel,3500.0,,2018,12,[],
9835,2018-12-17,Corpus Christi Ship Channel Vacuum Oil Discharge,"Corpus Christi, TX , USA",27.82222222,-97.43555556,Oil,Vacuum Gas Oil,210.0,,2018,12,[],
9834,2018-12-14,FV Atlantic Sapphire,Georges Bank,42.13,-67.10833333,Oil,,,"Ob December 13, 2018, the NOAA SSC was contacted by Canadian Coast Guard regarding the sinking of the FV Atlantic Sapphire near the US/Canada border in heavy seas.  The crew was rescued and the vessel sank with 8000 liters (2113 gallons) of diesel fuel.  The sinking  is almost 150 miles from the US coast and over 100 miles from the Canadian coast.  Canadian Coast Guard to overfly the region.",2018,12,,"[('December 13, 2018', 'DATE'), ('Canadian Coast Guard', 'ORG'), ('the FV Atlantic Sapphire', 'LOC'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('Canada', 'GPE'), ('8000', 'CARDINAL'), ('2113 gallons', 'QUANTITY'), ('almost 150 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('US', 'GPE'), ('over 100 miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Canadian', 'NORP'), ('Canadian Coast Guard', 'ORG')]"
9836,2018-12-14,TPIC Garden Island Bay Facility,"1, LA, USA",29.14083333,-89.19638889,Oil,Crude Oil,420.0,,2018,12,[],
9833,2018-12-12,DOD-contracted Aircraft crash,"off Honolulu, Hawaii",21.27033333,-157.92516669999998,Oil,jet fuel or aviation gasoline,900.0,,2018,12,[],
9832,2018-10-12,FV Nordic Viking,"Seward, AK",60.12004,-149.43491,Oil,diesel,700.0,,2018,10,[],
